<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<urlset xmlns="http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:video="http://www.google.com/schemas/sitemap-video/1.1">

  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/BeachDiving</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.8000</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/hFr5w9KLEA4/mqdefault_live.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Pompano Beach Underwater Pier Cam</video:title>
         <video:description>WELCOME! 

Dive into the deep with our new live stream from the City of Pompano Beach&apos;s underwater camera, located 15 feet beneath the Fisher Family Pier! 🌊🐠🎥 Please note that swimming, snorkeling, and diving are prohibited within 100 feet of the pier (§ 98.12 of City Code).

***************************************************************************************************************************************
LIVE CHAT:

Spot something cool? Drop the date and time in the chat. The camera view changes a few times a day, so there&apos;s always something new to see!

Please note: Our chat is meant for spotting sea creatures only. To participate in the chat, please subscribe to our channel and follow our social media policy guidelines at https://www.pompanobeachfl.gov/government/strategic-communications/social-media-policy.

***************************************************************************************************************************************

MORE INFO:

For more info on the underwater camera, visit www.pompanobeachfl.gov/press-release/city-of-pompano-beachs-new-underwater-camera-dives-into-hidden-ocean-world-shipwreck-park-donates-high-resolution-webcam.

For more info on the Fisher Family Pier, visit parks.pompanobeachfl.gov/facilities/fisher-family-pier.

To explore our other beach cams above the surface, swim over to www.pompanobeachfl.gov/webcams.

***************************************************************************************************************************************</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-05-13T21:12:38Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/hFr5w9KLEA4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>P0D</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/50</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/yIayD_FvBuI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>VR360 - Fishing Pier Reef in Lauderdale-by-the-sea, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>Beautiful shallow reef north of the fishing pier in Lauderdale-by-the-sea in Florida. This is a shore dive  - only 400 feet swimming from shore.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-08-28T22:52:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/yIayD_FvBuI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>807</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/51</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Ukztp4fG7SI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>VR360 - Erojacks in Dania Beach, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>Just 800 ft from the shoreline, there is a great artificial reef: the Dania Beach Erojacks. This site is home to turtles, lobsters, nurse sharks and all kind of tropical fish. Enjoy a 360 VR tour of this site - it&apos;s only 15 to 20 feet deep (perfect for the Open Water diver)</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-05-30T00:54:40Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ukztp4fG7SI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>876</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/104</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/QbH7S5L58s0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Vista Park Reef | Scuba Diving | Fort Lauderdale | Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Vista Park Reef | Scuba Diving | Fort Lauderdale | Florida

http://sinkfloridasink.com/south-florida-dive-sites/south-florida-beach-dives/vista-park-fort-lauderdale-scuba-diving-beach-dive-site/

The Vista Park Reef Beach Dive:
Vista Park Reef in Fort Lauderdale is very wide and runs North-South for about 800 yards. To get to the reef, swim straight out from the park&apos;s beach access for about 70-100 yards. The park entrance is roughly the middle point of the reef. This is a great beach dive site if you want to explore and don&apos;t want a strict dive plan to follow. This dive site primarily contains vast expanses of corals and other plant life, as well as an abundance of fish. Vista Park Reef is best for scuba diving and is not recommended for snorkeling.

No lifeguards on duty. You MUST use a dive flag when scuba diving at Vista Park Reef in Fort Lauderdale.

What You May See At Vista Park Reef In Fort Lauderdale:
Flamingo Tongue, damsels, grunts, soft coral, fan coral, urchins, conch

Vista Park Reef | Scuba Diving | Fort Lauderdale | Florida</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-06-17T11:14:47Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/QbH7S5L58s0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>130</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/105</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/JLcGMxBGP0E/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Yankee Clipper Rocks | Ft Lauderdale Snorkeling Beach Dive</video:title>
         <video:description>Yankee Clipper Rocks | Fort Lauderdale Snorkeling Beach Dive Site

**As of 6/22/2014, the Yankee Clipper Rocks are covered in sand due many rough ocean currents and storms. The video below was taken at a small 20ft scetion of reef which was not covered. It&apos;s infront of the firehouse. 

The Yankee Clipper Rocks Snorkeling Beach Dive:
The Yankee Clipper Rocks are located in Fort Lauderdale, and are a popular South Florida snorkeling location. You may enter the water at the south end of the parking lot. Starting at 150 feet offshore, you&apos;ll find a the natural rocky reef full of fish and coral.

You MUST use a dive flag when snorkeling the Yankee Clipper Rocks in Fort Lauderdale.

Directions to the Yankee Clipper Rocks Beach Dive Location:
Take I-95 to Davie Blvd. and head east. Make a right onto Federal Highway / US1 then make a left onto N. Ocean Blvd. / A1A. Follow the road for about 2 miles and keep an eye open for the signs to the public beach parking on the east side of A1A. Park as far south as possible.

What You May See When Snorkeling the  Fort Lauderdale Yankee Clipper Rocks:
Porkfish, Sergeant Majors, Scorpionfish, Nurse Sharks, French Angelfish

Music by Dust Trail: Our Track Through Time

Yankee Clipper Rocks | Fort Lauderdale Snorkeling Beach Dive Site</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-06-30T18:37:14Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/JLcGMxBGP0E</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>178</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/52</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-nLXQlrTrh0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving Under The Blue Heron Bridge</video:title>
         <video:description>We go down to Florida to see what&apos;s so special about The Blue Heron Bridge.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-01-01T22:45:31Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/-nLXQlrTrh0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>365</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/81</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/s499UyUZT7s/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Snorkeling Ocean Reef Park | Riviera Beach / Singer Island</video:title>
         <video:description>Snorkeling Ocean Reef Park | Riviera Beach / Singer Island

http://sinkfloridasink.com/south-florida-dive-sites/ocean-reef-park-riviera-beach-singer-island-snorkeling-site

The Riviera Beach / Singer Island Ocean Reef Park Snorkeling Beach Dive:
The reef at Ocean Reef Park is small and extremely close to shore. Even at high-tide, beach-goers can see the reef protruding from the ocean. Due to it&apos;s location and free parking, this is a very popular spot on the weekends. Ocean Reef Park is a shallow beach dive which is protected by lifeguards. It&apos;s great for beginners and non-Florida natives.

If you live and dive in Florida, this reef can be missed. It&apos;s full of people of all ages, swimming around and walking on the reef. Because it&apos;s so close to shore and people stirring up the sand, visibility at Ocean Reef Park is marginal.

This Singer Island snorkeling site is best around high tide. Scuba diving is not permitted at Ocean Reef Park, but snorkeling and free diving are.

NO NEED FOR A DIVE FLAG! (You must stay west of the swim buoy)

Snorkeling Ocean Reef Park | Riviera Beach / Singer Island</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-07-09T17:01:55Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/s499UyUZT7s</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>102</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/98</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-WLw_0w3CBI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Ocean Inlet Park Snorkeling | Boynton Beach</video:title>
         <video:description>Ocean Inlet Park Snorkeling | Boynton Beach

http://sinkfloridasink.com/south-florida-dive-sites/south-florida-beach-dives/ocean-inlet-park-boynton-beach-dive-site/

The reef at Ocean Inlet Park in Boynton Beach is an artificial reef constructed of giant boulders. This mitigation reef was a 5-month project that was completed in January 2010. The north end of the Ocean Inlet Park reef is less than a 5-minute walk from the South Lake Worth Inlet (Boynton Inlet). The reef is about 375 feet out from the beach and sits in 6 to 12 feet of water. Entering the water in front of the third set of rocks on the beach is recommended. This will allow you to tell where the current is coming from, while not over shooting the reef. From the beach and while in the water, you are able to see the dark areas in the ocean which is the reef.

Due to the Ocean Inlet Park reef&apos;s proximity to the inlet, this is a busy boating area and you MUST use a dive flag when scuba diving and snorkeling here.

Ocean Inlet Park Snorkeling | Boynton Beach</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-07-28T23:37:20Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/-WLw_0w3CBI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>132</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/250</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/hGXoHSWPaBI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Mar A Largo artificial reef dive on August 21, 2022</video:title>
         <video:description>Mar-A-Largo AKA P.E.P reef 
My first dive I had a pole spear and no camera so naturally I saw 20 plus nurse sharks resting on the bottom. In the next 2 dives we explored the southern portion of this reef and 2 small hammerhead sharks were also sighted. While this is a shallow dive of only up to 30 ft. it was a very interesting dive. Fish were plentiful and many large rays were sighted. While the mooring balls were gone one was found on the bottom in the reef. There is a 200 ft. gap between this reef and the next reef to the north which I am told is mostly made up of reef balls.

GPS numbers for the P.E.P. portion of the reef; 26 40.668 north, 80 1.783 west

P.E.P. general info
 A prefabricated erosion prevention P.E.P. reef was installed during the summer months of 1992 and 1993, at the Town of Palm Beach in Palm Beach County, FL. The reef was constructed at the Midtown segment of the Palm Beach Shore Protection Project. The structure consists of 330 interlocking wedge-shaped concrete modules placed approximately 76 m 250 ft offshore, in 2.9 m 9.4 ft National Geodetic Vertical Datum NGVD of water. The total length of the structure is 1,273 m 4,176 ft, including a 66-m 216-ft gap near the north end for a submerged cable easement. The purpose of the structure is to reduce incident wave energy, allowing accretion of sediment in the lee of the structure. 
Source: DEFENSE TECHNICAL INFORMATION CENTER</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-09-11T20:09:42Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/hGXoHSWPaBI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>241</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/288</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/_MjnHseOmrE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>loftus snorkel</video:title>
         <video:description>Shipwreck from late 1800&apos;s about a mile north of Boynton Inlet in 12 to 15 feet of water. Easy to swim to from beach...but most divers don&apos;t want to walk a mile north of the inlet, down the beach :-)
By boat, this is awesome for snorkeling.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-07-14T15:55:24Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/_MjnHseOmrE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>81</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/386</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/taxAdCynB-Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive The Adolphus Busch Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2011-09-06T16:09:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/taxAdCynB-Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>309</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/127</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Lzy_DM5CyW8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Almirante Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Almirante Wreck Scuba Dive

July 19, 1943: Launched by Cochrane and Sons, Limited, in Selby, United Kingdom, as the H.M.S. Gillstone (T355).

November 19, 1943: Commissioned into the Royal Navy, was an Isles Class trawler.

1947: Named was changed to Argo upon her sale to a Norwegian company.

1952: Converted to a refrigerated cargo ship.

1961: Renamed to Freedom First

1964: Renamed to Glenrock

1969: Renamed to Sea Enterprise

1970: Finally renamed as, Almirante when purchased by Miami Maritime and then, after only a few years, however, her owners abandoned her on the Miami River.

April 13, 1975: After numerous unsuccessful attempts to have Miami Maritime move their neglected vessel, the city of Miami had the upper decks of the Almirante’s superstructure removed, and they then towed the derelict offshore and sunk it as an artificial reef.

1992: Hurricane Andrew hits the wreck, twisting the stern to port and collapsing the center of the ship.

 

The Wreck: One of the older artificial reefs off Miami, the Almirante sits mostly upright off Elliott Key. Its stern is twisted to port and portions have partially collapsed amidships due to the influence of Hurricane Andrew, which passed over the site in August 1992. It is blanketed by abundant gorgonian growth, and other associated marine life is generally quite robust.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-09T19:29:28Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lzy_DM5CyW8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>214</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/38</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/1zuLS7kYEu4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Quallman Tugs 6-2-19</video:title>
         <video:description>With South Florida Diving Headquarters and Gold Coast Scuba, a truley epic dive on the Quallman Tugs. We saw Lemon Sharks, giant schools of spade fish, lobster, eels, large schools of snapper, grunt and ballyhoo and other reef life. There was also a hammerhead on the periphery but was not able to be captured on film unfortunately. 

Location: Pompano Beach

Description: This site has two old pusher tugs (32&apos;L), dredge pipe pontoons, fiberglass yacht hulls, and 2 steel sailboat hulls. The 2 steel sailboat hulls were broken apart by Hurricane Andrew and scattered 75 ft apart, bow to bow in several pieces. The Dorman lies on it&apos;s port side broken up pointing north. The Alpha (85&apos;L) is the second sailboat and is flattened. Some Captains nickname this site the &quot;Bone Yard&quot;. Spear fishermen beware this is a good spot to see bull sharks. If you have air and time remaining you can actually finish your dive on the adjacent reef.

History: The Quallman Tugs were sank on January 4, 1985. The Alpha was added to the wreckage on February 28, 1988. The Alpha was used in WWII to spot submarines near the Bahamas.

Song: &apos;It&apos;s Always Too Late to Start Over&apos; by Chris Zabriskie is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution license (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/)
Source: http://chriszabriskie.com/dtv/
Artist: http://chriszabriskie.com/ 
*description courtesy of www.southfloridaddiving.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-06-11T02:09:58Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/1zuLS7kYEu4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>302</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/265</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/E8J_bMCDbvA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Mizpah wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>Mizpah wreck, Palm Beach Florida

Sunk back in 1968, the Mizpah is the Palm Beach Coast’s oldest artificial reef. While only 60 percent of her former 160-foot hull remains intact, the wreck holds a luxuriant skin of living sponges and corals. Close by is the wreck of the PC-1174, an old patrol craft near the same size as the Mizpah that was sunk later the same year. In the years since, the PC-1174 has broken into several pieces, with the largest piece actually lying under the bow of the Mizpah.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-04-18T15:13:35Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/E8J_bMCDbvA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>225</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/82</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/8RkIcmYwaGw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>The Ana Cecilia artificial reef | New diving gem in The Palm Beaches</video:title>
         <video:description>Many thanks to Scuba Nation for sharing their underwater and aerial video! The Ana Cecilia cargo ship, once used in both an attempt to smuggle $10 million worth of cocaine on the Miami River and as the first ship to carry cargo from Miami to Cuba in 2012 after 50 years of embargo, now has a new destiny underwater off the coast of The Palm Beaches as an artificial reef. The Ana Cecilia is the 45th ship to be scuttled in Palm Beach County (PBC) in recent decades, drawing divers away from natural reefs, ensuring their sustainability. The Palm Beaches are home to 151 artificial reefs, including the Ana Cecilia, which provide a fascinating experience for divers. Plaques have been affixed to the ship, with sentiments honoring local community members Perry J. Cohen, Austin Stephanos, Palm Beach County Sheriff’s Office Deputy Fernandez Jones, Jaden Jones and Willis Bell, who are missing or lost at sea.
 
The ship was sunk on July 13, 2016, 1.25 miles off the Lake Worth Inlet in 85 feet of water (coordinates: 26 47.118/-80 00.960), where it is in the natural process of becoming an additional marine habitat as part of the artificial reef system managed by the Palm Beach County Department of Environmental Resources Management (ERM). Divers are welcome to explore this new underwater gem, which is expected to attract marine life within 48 hours after the sinking. The wealth of marine biodiversity is a unique attribute to The Palm Beaches’ coast, because of the County’s close proximity to the Atlantic Ocean’s Gulf Stream – considered an oceanic conveyor belt of warm water and artery for its natural residents to migrate, such as sea-turtles, tropical fish, sailfish, goliath grouper, dolphins and more.
 
The Ana Cecilia is a 170-foot Halter Marine general cargo ship built in 1972. Homeland Security Investigations (HSI), the lead investigative agency in the Department of Homeland Security responsible for conducting narcotic smuggling investigations in the maritime environment, led an investigation targeting the importation of narcotics in coastal freighters into the United States via the Miami River. As a result of findings, HSI requested assistance from U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) for the extensive search of the motor vessel Ana Cecilia. In September 2015, CBP searched the vessel and found 386 bricks of cocaine with a street value of more than $10 million, which led to the seizure of the cargo ship.
 
CBP administratively forfeited the ship in January 2016. The Treasury Executive Office for Asset Forfeiture approved the transfer of the vessel to Palm Beach County in support of the Artificial Reef Strategic Plan in March 2016. After approval by the Palm Beach County Board of County Commissioners, the ship was transferred to county ownership in May 2016. The captain and owner of the Ana Cecilia, Ernso Borgella, was indicted and pleaded guilty to one count of conspiracy to distribute cocaine and was sentenced to nine years in prison.
  
“The Ana Cecilia will soon become a diver’s dream, bustling with underwater activity as she is colonized by algae, sponges, and corals to support a diverse community of colorful marine life including Goliath Grouper, sea turtles, thorny oysters, and green moray eels,” explained Palm Beach County Environmental Resources Management
Division Director Julie O. Bishop.
 
“Divers come from all over the world to experience the unparalleled reefs of The Palm Beaches, whether natural or artificial,” said Jorge Pesquera, president and CEO for Discover The Palm Beaches, the official tourism marketing corporation for Palm Beach County. “Our area is geographically the closest land mass to the Gulf Stream in North America, and that magical current allows divers to see here a wide diversity of abundant marine life.”
 
“Our clear waters and fascinating marine biodiversity are just some of the reasons why divers choose to visit this destination,” continued Pesquera. “The Ana Cecilia’s unique history, as well as its honorable tribute to beloved community members who are missing or lost at sea, make it a unique addition to our artificial reef system.”</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-07-14T18:57:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/8RkIcmYwaGw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>78</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/4</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/RCp1N_E-xco/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Ancient Mariner Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>https://www.wreckwiki.com/wreck/Ancient-Mariner

HISTORY
Launched: July 7, 1934, by the Marietta manufacturing Company at Point Pleasant, West Virginia.
Commissioned: October 10, 1934, serving during World War II on the Gulf Sea Frontier.
May 21, 1942, rescued 28 survivors from the sunken tanker Faja de Oro

June 7, 1942, picked up 27 survivors from the torpedoed freighter Suwied

January 24 to August 17, 1942, engaged in six separate depth charge attacks against enemy U-boats in the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico.

Finished the war on escort duty between Key West and New York

Following World War II, patrolled between Florida and Cuba enforcing US. law, conducting search and rescue operations, and aiding Cuban refugees.

1964: Sold to Auto Marine Engineering, Incorporated of Miami

1979: Opened as a restaurant in Fort Lauderdale River

1981: Sunk at the dock

1986: 97 diners were infected with Hepatitis A, then closed. It was the largest food-borne hepatitis outbreak in Florida’s history.

​

Name History:

U.S.C.G.C. Nemesis (WPC‐111) (1934)

Livingston&apos;s Landing (1979)

Ancient Mariner (1981)

​

Divesite:

Now a popular dive site, the wreck is an easy dive with other wrecks in the near vicinity. The Ancient Mariner points to the southeast, and divers swimming off the bow will find the tug Berry Patch, as well as the remains of the Chuck A Luck II (formerly the River Queen) and the C-Note.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-23T21:57:44Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/RCp1N_E-xco</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>155</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/77</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/3se62B5gbhM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Ande wreck with Pura Vida Divers 072719</video:title>
         <video:description>Wreck diving a 190Ft wreck in the West Palm Beach FL area.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-30T23:39:24Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/3se62B5gbhM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>272</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/97</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/dnhf3vYZXd8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Andro Wreck Scuba Dive | North Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
Launched: October 11, 1925, by the Newport News Shipbuilding and Drydock Company

powered by two Winton diesel engines developing a total of 900 horsepower, yielding a cruising speed of 13 knots.

Five staterooms and four bathrooms for guests were located on the berth deck, while the dining saloon, livingroom, galley, and pantry were found on the main deck

1925: A biologist named Bingham originally explored the waters of the Caribbean, where he collected fish and other marine life

1926: Bigham conducted his second expedition to the Pacific coast of Central America and the Gulf of California.  Bingham had specially designed the Pawnee II to facilitate deep-sea trawling and research; a taxidermist’s room and laboratory were located on the main deck.

1927: third and final expedition took it to the Bahamas and Bermuda

1930: Bingham sold the ship

1938: the yacht was sold to the Virginia Pilots Association, converted into a pilot vessel

Early 1980s: operated as a freighter in the Bahamas

March 13, 1985: the U.S.C.G.C. Ute (WATF-76) conducted an inspection on the Andro after coming across the Bahamian‐ registered vessel in the Yucatan Straits, 40 miles southwest of Cuba, finding 15 tons of Marijuana.

December 17, 1985: purchased by the Miami‐Dade Department of Environmental Resources and sunk off Haulover Inlet

 

Name History:

Pawnee II (1925)

Hardi Biaoa (1930)

Virginia (1938)

Andro (n/a)

 

Divesite:

The once proud yacht now sits in 103 feet of water with her bow on her starboard side. Portions of the wreck rise almost 40 feet off the bottom. Amidships, the Andre’s funnel is resting practically upside down after it became dislodged from the hull. One of the vessel’s large engines can be found adjacent to the funnel. The Andro’s stern is listing to port with both screws still visible, though mangled. While she is largely remembered as a former drug-runner, it is fitting that the Andro, a vessel originally employed to further marine science, is now permanently serving as an artificial reef.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-11-01T21:11:21Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/dnhf3vYZXd8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>211</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/106</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/7TlvzL-IQTk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Belcher Barge, Miami</video:title>
         <video:description>This 185&apos; steel barge was sunk in November 1985 in the Key Biscayne area. The belcher barge was loaded with concrete pipes to add to the exploration of the dive but during the sinking process, she turned and landed completely upside down and the pipes rolled off to the South Side of the barge. The relief (height of wreck from the sand or bottom) is about 10 &apos;. There are many areas of penetration on this wreck, on the sides and through the hull. Inside the wreck are many areas to explore so make sure you bring a light (and a back up) and a safety reel. About mid ship on the South Side, where the pipes now lay, you can swim approx. 100 feet due South and you will run into the Belzona II.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-06-02T22:26:23Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/7TlvzL-IQTk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>62</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/121</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/duMPuKLmnCA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Key Biscayne - DPV Belzona Wreck Trek</video:title>
         <video:description>Join us on a beautiful morning diver propulsion vehicle wreck trek starting and ending at the Belcher Barge.

1. Belcher Barge 
2. Belzona II
3. Belzona I
4. Belzona III
5. Schruger&apos;s Barge
6. H.A.V. Parker III Barge

Miami-Dade Reef &amp; Buoy Finder: https://gisweb.miamidade.gov/artificialreefs/

Remember  to subscribe and hit that bell button!

Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/floridareel/
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/floridareel/
Website - https://thefloridareel.com/</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-04-09T18:12:38Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/duMPuKLmnCA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>441</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/120</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/fImp68kHYGw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Belzona Barge Miami, FL - B.O. Divers</video:title>
         <video:description>Bahamas Overseas diver Sam McLean guiding an excellent diver on the Belzona Barge and the Rainbow on the 27th of April 2014</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-05-09T10:54:53Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/fImp68kHYGw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>88</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/65</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/mYMiuSHrLYI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive the Wreck of the Benwood, Off Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description>Whet your appetite for some Florida Keys Wreck Diving!  Fish, fish and more fish! During World War II there was considerable German U-boat activity off the Florida coast, and in attempting to avert the notice of enemy submarines, the Benwood was operating blacked-out, without running lights, when she was rammed by a similarly darkened Robert C. Tuttle. The crew steered the Benwood toward shore in hopes of beaching her before she sank. On April 9, 1942, the Benwood instead became another of Key Largo&apos;s wondrous dive sites, this one in just 35 feet of water.  Video by Frazier Nivens</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-03-30T14:17:53Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/mYMiuSHrLYI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>56</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/405</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/4_p5H7x4CD4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Berry Patch Wreck Dive | Site Guide and Review |  Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>https://www.wreckwiki.com/wreck/Berry-Patch-Tug

HISTORY
Launched: 1940

Name History:
A.L. Spenser (1940)
Berry Patch (Divesite)
 
Divesite:
With a slight list to port, and is in close proximity to several other artificial reefs: the Ancient Mariner is approximately 150 feet to the northwest, the 40 foot long work boat C‐Note is approximately 100 feet to the north, and the 50‐foot long houseboat Chuck-A-Luck II is approximately 150 feet to the southwest. However, both the C‐Note and the Chuck-A-Luck II are largely flattened and only consist of very low lying debris that may be hard to locate by divers in less than optimal visibility.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-23T21:57:42Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/4_p5H7x4CD4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>119</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/148</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/lfVeIz58yEU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Montaje: Tortuga - St Henry - Betek Ar Pen</video:title>
         <video:description>Este es el montaje, solo con música, del episodio 17  de Buceando Ando.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-09-20T13:14:16Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/lfVeIz58yEU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>195</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/67</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/kBnswjLBLf8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Montaje: USCG BIBB</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-06-14T12:39:36Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/kBnswjLBLf8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>184</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/305</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/AnMHBuuHvJg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>GLASRUD REEF MAY 31, 2014</video:title>
         <video:description>Video monitoring by Wayne Turner volunteer for MCAC Reef Fund. 
The Glasrud Reef (formerly the BIG AL Tug) was placed in 187 ft south of the Wickstrom, 4 Towers, and the 3 rubble reefs. This will help to continue the line of deep water reefs in Martin County.

Despite the lack of government funding, groups like MCAC Reef Fund have found ways to raise money and continue placing artificial reefs off Martin County.

The NAMING RIGHTS for this reef belong to TED GLASRUD.
Location:
   N 27° 12.698 / W 80° 00.259
Built: 1954
Scuttled: 2.24.2010
Depth: 187 feet
Profile: 42&apos; from sea bottom
Beam at 19’ 
Draft of 9’
Materials: Steel Hull</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-09-20T00:15:09Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/AnMHBuuHvJg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>222</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/155</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/WA6QWsCXXuw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>BlueFire Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>https://www.wreckwiki.com/wreck/Blue-Fire

HISTORY
June 1980, the freighter Blue Fire traveled to Cuba as part of a ”Freedom Flotilla” during the Mariel Boat Lift, and was expected to leave the Communist island with up to 5,000 refugees thought to be headed for Florida.

July 5, 1980: was intercepted by the US. Coast Guardon, approximately 37 miles south of Cuba as it steamed for the Cayman Islands after departing from Mariel Harbor.

July 9, 1980: Mysteriously appeared at Miami under Coast Guard escort, with no exiles and was occupied only by its seven crewmen

Seized by the US. government, the Blue Fire was eventually transferred for use as an artificial reef.

 

Divesite:

The wreck of the freighter Blue Fire is testament to the power of an intense hurricane. Less than 10 years after its deployment as an artificial reef near Fowey Rocks in January 1983, Hurricane Andrew smashed into the hull of the freighter. The wreck was significantly impacted: the aft bridge superstructure was ripped from the lower hull and stern; amidships, the cargo hold reveals a prominent bend, as the storm swell attempted to fold the vessel in half; and the bow is kicked hard over to starboard.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-08-04T21:31:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/WA6QWsCXXuw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>200</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/109</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/8nwHrDrFe1A/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: BrandyWine (Miami , Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Launched: 1949

Along with the Miguana, Etoile De Mer, and the Tacoma, were seized by the US. Customs Service due to their use in smuggling drugs into Florida via the Miami River.

 Divesite:
The Brandywine is one of four vessels sunk as artificial reefs in an area off Key Biscayne known as US. Customs Reef.
On February 12, 2001, Customs inspectors discovered a false compartment under a waste oil tank in the forward cargo hold of the Brandy Wine. The Brandy Wine was sent to the bottom following the detonation of scuttling charges on July 13, 2001. She now rests upright and intact in 145 feet of water. The small wheelhouse and superstructure grace the bow of the vessel. Swimming west off the stern of the Brandy Wine, divers will encounter the 101-foot long Miguana.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-08-03T04:16:29Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/8nwHrDrFe1A</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>307</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/231</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/0yRWZqzvOC8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the “King of Beers” the Budweiser Bar Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>Budweiser Bar Wreck or M/S Havel in Boynton, FL</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-05-28T21:26:18Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yRWZqzvOC8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>339</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/192</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Ajb_e7Es5lE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Lionfish on The Bulk Trader</video:title>
         <video:description>The Bulk Trader is an artificial wreck located about 3.7nm north east of Port Everglades.  It was sunk in 2002 in 323 ft. of water.  There are lots of Lionfish.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-10-28T17:36:03Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ajb_e7Es5lE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>185</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/167</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/kLhYFo91IFY/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>C-One Wreck Scuba Dive | North Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>The C‐One was a tug purchased by the Miami-Dade Department of Environmental Resources Management for use as an artificial reef.

The aged tug was stripped of her engine and fittings in late 1990 and then towed from Jacksonville to Miami by the tug Captain Donald in preparation of her scuttling. On November 3, 1990, while approximately five miles southeast of Fort Pierce Inlet, the 60‐foot long Captain Donald began taking on water, which flooded into her engine room. The three crew members were forced to abandon ship as the Captain Donald quickly sank underneath them. The still-floating C‐One was eventually towed to Miami following the ironic event.

The C-One was finally dispatched on November 8, 1990. She was sunk in 68 feet of water off Haulover Inlet in the vicinity of several other artificial reefs.

The C‐One is straddled by the tug Lady Carmen, resting just to the west, and the 38-foot long tug White Coast, found just to the east. The two sections of the 155-foot long freighter Conception are found less than 200 feet to the north of the C‐One. In addition, a 90-foot long barge and numerous concrete modules lie a short distance to the southeast.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-11-04T14:27:27Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/kLhYFo91IFY</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>124</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/110</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/0L8ObnRX9nU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Dive: Caicos Express (Pompano Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>🌊 Welcome to another ISDC video! Join us as we dive deep into the waters of Pompano Beach, Florida, to explore the mysterious Caicos Express wreck in stunning 4k!

📍 *Introduction:* 0:00
Embark on an underwater journey with Alejandro and ISDC as we unveil the secrets of the sunken Caicos Express.

📍 *Dive Brief:* 00:46
Discover dive essentials and Caicos Express specifications, essential for understanding this dive&apos;s depth and ideal conditions.

📍 *The Dive Itself:* 01:57
Descend with us into the depths, uncovering the Caicos Express wreck and its vibrant marine life as we delve as deep as possible.

📍 *History of the Wreck:* 04:45
Explore the intriguing history behind this sunken marvel.

📍 *Conclusion:* 05:52

Gear Used:
- Camera: Panasonic Lumix GH6 (#panasonicgh6) @ChannelPanasonic
- Lights: Big Blue @bigbluedivelights7268
- Housing: Nauticam #nauticam

🐠 #UnderwaterExploration #WreckDiving #PompanoBeach #RenegadeWreck #Shipwreck #DivingAdventure #OceanDiscovery #ExploreTheUnknown #ScubaDiving #underwaterhistory #nauticam

Don&apos;t forget to like, comment, and subscribe for more thrilling underwater adventures! Follow us on Instagram and Facebook for exclusive behind-the-scenes content and dive deeper into the Caicos Express&apos; intriguing story. 🚢🔍🌊

*ISDC Instagram*:
www.instagram.com/internationalscubadiversclub
*ISDC Facebook*:
www.facebook.com/internationalscubadiversclub

=======================
*Edition*
Facundo Mercado Spinella
facumercadospinella@gmail.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-04-25T13:32:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/0L8ObnRX9nU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>389</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/73</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/i_KVt9TnWkk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Capitan Dan Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>One of the most traditional dive sites in south florida: the Captain Dan Wreck

Closest Inlet: Hilsboro</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-05-20T22:49:19Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/i_KVt9TnWkk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>168</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/180</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/mGHbfB4DTGU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>BuceandoAndo 10: Naufragios de Hollywood - Florida (25 metros)</video:title>
         <video:description>Volvemos a bucear en la costa de Florida, en los Estados Unidos! Esta vez vamos al arrecife artificial formado por varios pecios (naufragios artificales) en la costa de la localidad de Hollywood.

En este video hay varias secciones, para ir directo a ellas:

0:00 Intro
0:46 Detalle del arrecife
2:07 La Inmersión
5:52 La Entrada en la Bitácora</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-04-14T12:26:26Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/mGHbfB4DTGU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>433</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/395</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/gARS5R9sk5k/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving Cayman Salvage Master Wreck Key West 5.21.24</video:title>
         <video:description>A little tour of the Cayman Salvage Master Wreck. A first time for me at this site. Diving with Lost Reef Adventures with Captain Hal and Divemasters Dave and Holly.




Making a digitized version of my memories to keep them intact for all eternity.







948</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-05-22T03:26:55Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/gARS5R9sk5k</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>549</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/269</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/h0ZMgYL1icM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Korimu Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>Wreck diving, deep tech diving, scuba, 
the wreck is located just out of the Riviera Beach inlet north of West Palm Beach Florida. this is a deep wreck at 235Ft and requires mixed gasses and advanced certifications.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-06-22T01:47:40Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/h0ZMgYL1icM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>179</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/56</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/kEfPkP-BvQg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>City Of Washington shipwreck, Elbow Reef, Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-09-19T15:46:32Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/kEfPkP-BvQg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>101</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/174</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Zyw3ZiaWHeo/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Cruz del Sur Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | North Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>wreckwiki.com/wreck/Cruz-Del-Sur

HISTORY
Launch: July 7, 1956 by Lindenau (Germany)
March 3, 1985: Seized by the US. Coast Guard for smuggling drugs

Name History:
Tronstad (1956)
Eva (1962)
Caribbean Tamanaco (1969)
Cruz del Sur (1977)

Divesite: The wreck of the Cruz del Sur is one of the more impressive deep artificial reefs off South Florida.  As the sinking of the Cruz del Sur was a joint project between Miami-Dade and Broward Counties, the former freighter was deployed basically on the border of the two counties and less than one mile south of the Tenneco Towers site. The Cruz sits upright and intact, with her forward kingposts reaching to within 140 feet of the surface. Due to her location approximately seven miles south of Port Everglades, visibility is generally excellent over the wreck. While the cargo holds are largely bare, aside from some scattered hatch covers resting under a layer of fine silt, the decks of the wreck are adorned by a colorful layer of invertebrate growth, which hosts swarms of small tropical fish.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-08-19T03:16:42Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zyw3ZiaWHeo</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>220</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/267</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/q0uWV3obwMI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Danny Tugboat Wreck, August 2021</video:title>
         <video:description>The Danny McCauley Memorial Reef has been deployed in less than 80 feet of water just north of the Lake Worth inlet. The tugboat sits in 79 feet of seawater with the deck in the 50-foot range. This 110 foot World War II vintage tugboat, formerly called the M/V Pocahontas was built in Ontario, Canada, in 1944. The M/V Pocahontas now lies in 74 feet of water less than two miles northeast of Lake Worth Inlet. This area is home to other artificial reefs, including the first vessels sunk by the county in the 1960s, large concrete pieces from the old Royal Park Bridge, several barges and a small tugboat.
 
The M/V Pocahontas will provide a stepping stone between the older reef placements to the south and the Royal Park Bridge materials to the north. After several delays due to Coast Guard inspections, mechanical failures, and weather, the decision was made to sink the tugboat the morning of February 22, 2013. The choice of this date was unintentional but somehow fitting. It was the anniversary of the passing of 16-year-old Danny McCauley in a tragic automobile accident, in which the site is named after.
 
Danny “Daniel” McCauley was an avid fishermen and diver whose life was cut short at the age of 17 in a tragic automobile accident while on the way to school in 2012. Many of his classmates at Palm Beach Central High School knew and loved him for his good nature and camaraderie as a member of the varsity wrestling team. But his family and friends knew that the ocean was what Danny loved most.
 
As a mean to celebrate his life, the McCauley family donated $10,000 to the PBC’s Environmental Resources Management (ERM) for the acquisition of a new artificial reef, which the Diving Association was currently working on at the time. With the combined efforts of Palm Beach County’s Environmental Resources Management (ERM), the Doitfordanny.com fundraiser (where the McCauley family funds were derived), along with the PBCDA’s own non-profit Artificial Reef Fund (ARF), the objective to create a new dive site was made a reality. In addition to this tremendous initiative being shared by all parties, the decision to rename the wreck after Danny McCauley was equally unanimous.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-09-03T13:29:36Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0uWV3obwMI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>384</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/176</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/9H2cspWzq48/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dantor Wreck Scuba Dive | Hollywood, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
Launched: 1974, Netherlands

Siezed: January 31, 2001. The US. Customs Service followed a rental truck that had been loaded with 880 pounds of cocaine from the freighter.

 Name History:
Ameland (1974)
Afhanelijk (1988)
Dantor (1998)

Divesite:
The freighter now rests upright and intact in 128 feet of water.  Given that charters hardly ever visit it, it is said to have lots on life on it, and sadly lot of lionfish too.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-03-23T00:45:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/9H2cspWzq48</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>202</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/339</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/UfAyjNxrr4Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>David T Wreck Dive Stuart Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>The David T sits in 75&apos; out of Stuart Florida. Super cool wreck dive with big goliaths, AJs, gags, cobia and many small fish. There&apos;s plenty of room to explore inside the wreck. easy to hit on a drift since the wreck sites east/west, perpendicular to the prevailing North current. Video taken March 2016</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-03-21T22:49:28Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/UfAyjNxrr4Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>147</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/151</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/BOSv808Qlz8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Deep Freeze Tec Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>DEEP FREEZE Miami

The Deep Freeze was built in 1958 by J.J. Sietas Schiffswerft, in Hamburg. She was originally named Marie Horn and renamed in 1969 when she was sold. This diesel engine refrigerator freighter was owned by Trans Caribbean Lines of Monrovia and managed by Trans Caribbean Agencies of Miami. The Deep Freeze was 231 feet long, had a 33.5 foot beam and displaced 1,138 gross tons.

Lloyd&apos;s of London reports that she burnt off of Port Limon on July 1, 1972, and she was subsequently dismantled. She now rests in 135 feet of water with her top deck reachable at 100 feet.

Due to the monofilament lines on this wreck and the heavy buildup of silt, the Deep Freeze is only recommended for advanced divers. Be sure to bring a knife for the monofilament. Remember penetration into any shipwreck should only be done by those with proper training, experience and wreck diving equipment. Scuba equipment like powerful dive lights, navigation reels, dive knives as well as redundant air supply like a pony bottle or doubles are standard gear for wreck divers. Colonies of spiny oysters cover the deck of the wreck, and large fish such as grouper, jack and barracuda can also be seen.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-10-28T18:59:44Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/BOSv808Qlz8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>186</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/96</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Ar_cLUmdYg4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>#Wreck Diving: DEMA Trader (Miami, FL)</video:title>
         <video:description>Welcome to another International Scuba Divers Club (ISDC) video, this is the video of the DEMA Trader wreck in Miami, Florida:

0:00 Intro
0:30 Dive Briefing
2:40 Diving the Wreck
6:18 History of the Wreck

HISTORY
Launched: 1957 as a general cargo ship by Jadewerft Gmbh, Wilhelmshaven and owned by Behrmann R. &amp; W., Itzehoe
2003: seized by the US Customs Service for smuggling narcotics
October 28, 2003: In conjunction with the 2003 Dive Equipment and Marketing Association (D.E.M.A.) annual convention that was held in Miami, the G.D.D. Trader was renamed the D.E.M.A. Trader and sunk as an artificial reef off Key Biscayne.

Name History:
Alk (1957)
Martin M. (1990)
Mondia (1993)
GGD Trader (1998)
DEMA Trader (2003)
Divesite:

The wreck of the D.E.M.A. Trader rests upright and intact in approximately 80feet of water just to the north of the tug Rio Miami and to the west of the Sarah Jane artificial reef site. Large openings were cut in the sides of the superstructure to allow safe penetration into the former galley and cabin areas. Tons of concrete culvert pipes and junction boxes were also loaded into the ship’s cargo hold to produce additional complex habitat for marine life.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #trek 
#biscayne #southbeach #beach #scuba #divesite</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-07-16T11:30:06Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ar_cLUmdYg4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>478</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/204</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Rbt2xSoU8KU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Dewitt Clinton (Pompano Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>0:00 Intro 
0:35 Divesite Facts
1:36 Diving The Wreck
4:34 Diving into History 

HISTORY
Launched: October 31, 1910, by the Bethlehem Steel Company of Sparrows Point, Maryland, as a dredge and ordered by the Ellicott Machine Corporation
November 14, 1994: sank in the Cooper River near Charleston, South Carolina, and subsequently leaked a significant amount of diesel fuel into the river.
After salvage operations to prevent the further release of fuel, the dredge was raised, cleaned, and towed to Florida by Associated Marine Salvage, Incorporated of Miami.

Name History:
DeWitt Clinton was a nearly American politician who served in the United States Senate and was the sixth Governor of New York. During his tenure as governor, he was largely responsible for the construction of the Erie Canal.
This accomplishment, as  well as his contributions during his earlier work with the Erie Canal Commission, helps explain the naming of the dredge DeWitt Clinton.

Divesite:
The wreck has a double hull design, similar to a catamaran, but with squared‐offends possessing two big rings near the top and bottom that could host anchor pilings when in service. The interior of each hull pontoon has long, silty corridors that require care when exploring. The wheelhouse is large and has some interesting growth on it, making for an entertaining swim-through.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-10-27T10:00:15Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rbt2xSoU8KU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>376</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/86</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/qZQmvWZmcO0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Doc deMilly Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review |  Elliot Key, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Shipwreck Doc De Milly is a 287 foot long steel freighter that was built in 1949 under the name Nuevo Rio. Before its scuttling she was renamed to the Doc De Milly in memory of a local Miami veterinarian. The Department of Environmental Resource Management (DERM) scuttled her on March 6, 1986 by controlled charges and remote detonators. The United States Air Force flew by and showed the audience what an impact many concrete bombs can have on a ship this size. For them it was a training practice, while the people got an idea of the terror of war; it was of course a great event attracting many tourist and locals. Nowadays she is located several hundred yards east of the Pacific Reef Lighthouse, far into Biscayne National Park.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-06-16T22:14:08Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/qZQmvWZmcO0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>184</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/60</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ApTt0lLzpc8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Duane Wreck | Key Largo Wreck SCUBA Diving</video:title>
         <video:description>Duane Wreck | Key Largo Wreck SCUBA Diving 

Visit the link below to learn more about scuba diving the Duane Wreck.
https://goo.gl/L7p6qS

The Duane Wreck is one of the most popular wrecks in the Florida Keys. While it&apos;s not nearly as massive as the Spiegel Grove Wreck which rests 7 miles northeast, you can take an amazing visit on a single dive with 32% Nitrox. However, we recommend doing a double dip to really enjoy the beauty of the Duane Wreck.

History of the Duane Wreck:
The USCGC William J. Duane (WPG-33), better known as the Duane, was one of seven 327ft Coast Guard Cutters built between 1935-1936. This specific vessel&apos;s keel was laid on May 1, 1935 at the Philadelphia Navy Yard. She was then launched on June 3, 1936 as a search/rescue and law enforcement vessel.

These seven vessels were known as the &quot;Treasury/Secretary&quot; Coast Guard cutters which were all named after former Secretaries of the Treasury Department. The Duane was named for William John Duane, who served as the Secretary of the Treasury under President Andrew Jackson.

The Duane served the United States Coast Guard for 49 years and became one of the oldest warship in service. After servicing the United States for nearly half a century, her age began to show. Replacement parts were nearly nonexistent and the Coast Guard decided it would be more feasible to decommission the Duane than to keep putting money into this cutter.

The Duane was decommissioned on August 1, 1985 and was laid up in Boston for two years. On November 27, 1987 the Duane was deliberately sunk of the coast of Key Largo to create this amazing artificial reef we advance open water divers get to explore! Then On May 16, 2002 the Diane Wreck was added to the U.S. National Register of Historic Places.

Diving the Duane Wreck:
The amazing Duane Wreck rests upright at a maximum depth of 128ft. Her deck is around 102ft. The crow’s nest is close to 54ft and make sure to visit it as there&apos;s a hawks bill sea turtle that calls it home!

Duane Wreck | Key Largo Wreck SCUBA Diving</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-12-28T12:59:54Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/ApTt0lLzpc8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>212</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/298</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6pty4fvEaZM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Wreck of the Eagle</video:title>
         <video:description>&quot;Watch high-definition video of the wreck of the Eagle&quot;</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2011-08-30T18:13:49Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/6pty4fvEaZM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>106</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/177</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/WffHKgEGjiE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Ebenezer II in Fort Lauderdale</video:title>
         <video:description>WELCOME ABOARD!  We’re Andrew and Laura – two professional scuba divers and ocean enthusiasts. Join us as we share wild stories, ocean views, and useful tips with you from under (and above) the sea!

· · · ·
The Ebenezer II is a 95&apos; shipwreck in southern Broward County in South Florida.  The dive site is best accessed from Port Everglades via a dive operator from Fort Lauderdale.

Not much is known about the history of the Ebenezer other than it was sunk in 2002 as a part of Broward County’s Artificial Reef Program south of Port Everglades Inlet. Its life prior to sitting on the ocean floor is a bit of a mystery.

After fluttering to the sandy bottom on May 14, 2002, the Ebenezer sits fully intact listing to its starboard side with its bow facing directly south. Keep this in mind if you’re looking to penetrate the halls below deck as they’ll be slanted at a 45° angle due to the listing.

Speaking of penetration, the Ebenezer is the ideal shipwreck for practicing wreck entry in Fort Lauderdale. The cargo bays below are blown out, the wheelhouse is open, and a tight entry point exists in the main cabin. It’s an exciting adventure for those seeking some overhead environments in their dive adventures!

For more on this dive site, visit our Dive Guide page at:
https://fortlauderdalediveguide.com/ebenezer-ii/

· · · ·

Dive in to explore an ocean lifestyle!
https://oceanwideexplorers.com

Subscribe to explore all the latest ocean adventures, dive sites and more!
https://oceanwideexplorers.com/subscribe/

Follow us on Instagram to learn more about ocean-friendly lifestyles!
https://instagram.com/oceanwideexplorers/

Say hello to us on our Facebook!
https://facebook.com/oceanwideexplorers

Discover your next ocean adventure on Pinterest!
https://pinterest.com/oceanwideexplorers/

Videos made by Laura, featuring Andrew!
https://www.instagram.com/lionfishlaura/
https://www.instagram.com/andrewbloem/

FAQ
What&apos;s our camera setup?
GOPRO: https://amzn.to/37VGG1A
LED LIGHT: https://amzn.to/2GisJ2l
HANDLE: https://amzn.to/324K3iT
WATERPROOF CASING AND FILTERS: https://amzn.to/2HOWUhY

What dive gear do we use?
BCD (for men): https://shrsl.com/2g7xx
BCD (for women): https://shrsl.com/2g7y1
REGULATOR: https://shrsl.com/2g7y4
OCTO: https://shrsl.com/2g7y5
PRESSURE GAUGE: https://shrsl.com/2g7y6
DIVE COMPUTER: https://shrsl.com/2g7y7
FINS: https://shrsl.com/2g7y8 and https://shrsl.com/2g7yb
MASK: https://shrsl.com/2g7yd and https://shrsl.com/2g7yh</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-11-30T15:24:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/WffHKgEGjiE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>100</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/359</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Z2QH8JEDaHA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Great Day Diving Erl King Wreck | Trying to Escape Bad Weather #freediving #snorkelling #shipwrecks</video:title>
         <video:description>Hi Everyone! Welcome!
My friends in this video I bring to you my best underwater images as well as  some interesting  facts about the Steamer Erl King. I included some anime clips to make more fun. Let me know if you like the new anime clips.
The Day was beautiful, It was sunny, warm and bright. The seas flat and the waters were crystal clear blue and aqua blue.er and perfect underwater swimming conditions.
In this Video Captain Miky and I go out to sea to check out another wreck. This time we went to check out Erl King&apos;s Shipwreck in Biscayne National Park, Miami. There we dived and swam underwater to admire the always amazing marine life and to enjoy the calm and quiet below the surface.
I hope you enjoy the video as I love to share these adventures with you with the hopes of bringing you some joy or a brief get away.
I love you!
SheViking
(Anna)</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-07-15T21:08:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z2QH8JEDaHA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>1338</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/92</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/QmWl6R4K134/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jupiter Scuba Diving - JUPITER WRECK TREK</video:title>
         <video:description>https://jupiterscubadiving.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-01-21T16:21:33Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/QmWl6R4K134</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>178</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/102</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/opCb5TCGmKs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Etoile de Mer (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>French for ”Star Fish,” the Etoile DeMer was an 80‐foot long former fishing vessel that was converted and used as an inter-island freighter in her later years. On January 18, 2001, the Etoile DeMer was seized after the US. Customs Service received an anonymous tip of suspicious activity on the ship, which was moored in the Miami River. As part of  ”Operation Riverwalk,” agents inspected the freighter and found 186 pounds of cocaine, worth $1.5 million wholesale, in two duffel bags hidden in a false wall between the cargo hold and the engine room. The vessel was seized by the US. government and eventually sunk along with two other Miami River narcotic-smuggling ships, the Brandy Wine and the Miguana, on July 13, 2001. The Etoile De Mer now rests in 135 feet of water off Key Biscayne at U S . Customs Reef, and is a short swim to the west of the Miguana; swimming east off the bow of the Etoile DeMer will take you to the bow of the Miguana. The Tacoma can be found by swimming approximately 500 feet to the northwest.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-07-19T23:18:51Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/opCb5TCGmKs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>322</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/370</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/rirrXPrSM6Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive The Vandenberg</video:title>
         <video:description>&quot;Watch high-definition video of the wreck of the Ge. Hoyt S. Vandenberg&quot;</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2011-08-30T18:12:53Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/rirrXPrSM6Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>66</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/260</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/C7VmVmbRsIs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Governors riverwalk 030120</video:title>
         <video:description>nice drift wreck dive in West Palm Beach with Pura Vida Divers at Blue Heron Bridge</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-03-03T02:14:08Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/C7VmVmbRsIs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>186</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/48</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/XHgmEcBiccY/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Guy Harvey Tec Wreck Scuba Dive | Pompano, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
Launched: 1957 as a coastal freighter at the Dutch shipyard of H.W. Bodewes, Martenshoek
1978: sold to a Denmark based company
1984: sold to a U.K. based company
1985: sold to a Honduras based company
1989: sold to an Anguilla based company
1992: sold to a Guyana based company
1997: sold to a Honduras based company again, but due to fatigue and neglect, the vessel had outlived her usefulness, and she was abandoned at Port‐au‐Prince, Haiti, later that year.

Name History:
Voorwaarts (1957)
Fredrika (1978)
Emma (1980)
Vicentian (1989)
Emma A (1989)
Endezo (1992)
Lady Kimberly (1997)

Divesite:
Named after marine artist Guy Harvey who helped fund and promote this artificial reef project.
The Pompano Beach Fishing Rodeo appropriated the vessel for use as an artificial reef and towed the crippled freighter back to Fort Lauderdale. Guy Harvey laid his artistic touch to the gutted vessel, painting billfish and sharks on its wheelhouse and hull. She now rests upright and intact, and encrusting organisms have long since covered over Harvey’s paintings.
May Storms had left a mark on the wreck and deterioration is becoming more noticeable.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-03-01T20:30:05Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/XHgmEcBiccY</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>188</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/325</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/KVthmlYqthQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Hailey Glasrud Reef dive August 23, 2014</video:title>
         <video:description>MCAC REEF BUILDERS    www.MCACREEFS.org
The HAILEY GLASRUD ARTIFICIAL REEF was deployed on April 24, 2014 in Martin County&apos;s Sirotkin site. This underwater video is just 4 months later by Kerry Dillon&apos;s Sea Rover Services.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-09-08T18:32:36Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVthmlYqthQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>649</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/142</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/fr8SccjqrL0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Half Moon Shipwreck in Miami</video:title>
         <video:description>This video is about 155ft German racing sail yacht built in 1908, sunken off of Bear Cut in Miami Beach, FL.

Find more information about the shipwreck by visiting National Park Services website below:

https://www.nps.gov/articles/halfmoon.htm</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-08-18T02:36:48Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/fr8SccjqrL0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>104</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/57</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/_QB363O036s/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>VR360 - Hannah M. Bell Wreck in Key Largo, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>Take a dive through this ancient wreck in Elbow Reef (Key Largo, FL).</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-04-11T00:41:59Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QB363O036s</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>872</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/34</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/NYzqiOJQdy8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Hog Heaven Wreck in Fort Lauderdale Scuba Diving</video:title>
         <video:description>Hog Heaven Wreck in Fort Lauderdale Scuba Diving

Click the link to learn more about the Hog Heaven Wreck:
https://goo.gl/b4YwVm

Located in Fort Lauderdale, the Hog Heaven Wreck is a mix of various items placed in an area over a span of three years. The main attraction of this wreck dive is the 180-foot Western Barge which was intentionally sunk on September 19, 1986 to become an artificial reef. The Hog Heaven Wreck flipped during it’s sinking and now rests upside down in 72 feet of water. It’s easy to penetrate with proper training. However, divers must exercise additional caution when penetrating the Hog Heaven Wreck due to it being an older wreck with a lot of sharp, mangled metal.

Hog Heaven Wreck in Fort Lauderdale Scuba Diving
Diving the Hog Heaven Wreck in South Florida
Hog Heaven
Hog Heaven Wreck</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-09-25T02:09:52Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/NYzqiOJQdy8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>197</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/1</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/zZNr6mJEap4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Hydro Atlantic (Boca Raton, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Welcome to the International Scuba Divers Club video.
This time we will be guiding all of you thru the mythical Hydro Atlantic #wreck.
The sections of this video:

0:00 Intro
1:23 Dive Briefing
2:24 Diving the Outside of the Wreck
6:07 Diving the Bow
7:50 Diving the Engine Room
10:14 Diving the Stern
11:54 History of the Wreck

HISTORY
Launched: 1905, at Yard 51 of the Sparrows Point, Maryland, facility of the Maryland Steel Company, official number 260377, as a US. Army Corps of Engineers’ hopper dredge to a maximum of 45 ft.
1922: it dredged 1,366 loads for the Philadelphia District, which removed a total of 2,378,593 cubic yards of material.
1950: Sold to Construction Aggregates Corporation
1961: Re-Built. The rebuild deepened her draft, increasing her hopper capacity from 3,076 cubic yards to approximately 5,000 cubic yards, and most likely rebuilt her superstructure, which was originally constructed of wood. The hopper dredge worked on the Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel project, dredging sand to help construct the man‐made islands for the tunnel.
1962: An engine caught fire and moved to New York for repairs.
1968: Sold to Hydromar Corporation of Delaware.
Later, condemned to a salvage yard for scrapping.

Name History:
Delaware (1905)
Sand Captain (1950)
Ezra Sensibar (1961)
Hydro Atlantic (1968)

Divesite:
As the Hydro Atlantic was being towed by the tug Elizabeth II to the scrap yard at Brownsville, Texas, her hull gave way and she sank in approximately one mile east of the Boca Raton Inlet on December 7, 1987. Apparently, the towing operation neglected to maintain the four pumps that were needed to keep the leaky 82-year old vessel afloat, and she began to wallow behind the tug. By the time the situation was recognized, it was too late. The tug parted the tow lines and the dredger quickly settled beneath the surface. Sitting bolt upright, the bow of the Hydro Atlantic points southward with her forward mast reaching to within 100 feet of the surface, while the deck is encountered at approximately 145 feet. The bridge and superstructure present several levels to explore, with the collapsed aft-facing bulkheads allowing easy entry in to the interior. Railing still lines the perimeter of the vessel. Moving aft, a large access hold is bordered by winches and other machinery. A large crane can be found along either side of the ship, the operator’s chair long since vacant. Swimming past the single stack, divers will encounter the engine room skylights, which present one of many points of entry into the interior of the ship. Dropping down past several catwalks and then moving forward, divers will be confronted with a large panel of gauges and controls that used to power the dredges on the ship. The boiler room can be found on the opposite side of this area. Heading towards the stern, there is an aft hold that allows abundant areas to explore. While divers have recovered numerous artifacts, there are still many brass fittings, gauges, and assorted material still remaining on the ship.  The wreck of the Hydro Atlantic is perhaps one of the most visually stunning wrecks in South Florida. The surfaces of the vessel have largely been incorporated by gorgonians, and areas appear very much like a pasture of purple sea fans that oscillate in the current. It is also interesting to note that exotic Indo‐Pacific fish species, such as moorish idols and yellow bar angelfish, have been observed on this wreck. This is most likely due to the wreck’s proximity to Boca Raton Inlet and the Intercoastal Waterway, where local aquarists may release their unwanted specimen fish. The moderate depth offers a wonderful wreck for initial technical training. Even veteran wreck divers will enjoy a dive on the Hydro.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-10-11T10:00:23Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/zZNr6mJEap4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>931</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/39</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/89_7iU2cIIs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>27. Ar 2016. Qualmann Tugs Wreck &amp; Wreck Trek Deerfield</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-04-28T03:05:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/89_7iU2cIIs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>262</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/37</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/BPsc43a7Kuw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jay Scutti Wreck Dive Ft. Lauderdale, FL 12.2.2023 #diving #scubadiving #wreckdiving #scuba</video:title>
         <video:description>Jay Scutti Wreck Dive Ft. Lauderdale, FL 12.2.2023 

Location: Fort Lauderdalle

Description: The Jay Scutti is 95&apos; long and sits upright with the bow pointing north. The Scutti is one of 4 wrecks in a line. The Pride is to the south and the Tracey and Merci Jesus are to the north. She is encrusted with invertebrates, sponges, hydroids and tunicates making this a favorite wreck for herbivorous fish like parrots.

History: The 95 foot Aruba harbor tugboat was built in 1961 in the Netherlands. Her original name was Arikok after the first settlers of Aruba. The Arikok was caught while on a marijuana smuggling mission and confiscated. She was later purchased at auction by a local businessman and renamed Jay Scutti, in memory of his son. The wreck was sunk as an artificial reef on September 19, 1986.

#scuba #underwater #underwaterworld #underwaterdiving #sea #seacreatures #scubadiving #underwater #scuba #scubadiving #sea #seacreatures #underwaterdiving #reef #reeffish #divingtrip #divingisfun #underwaterworld #diving
#ocean #sealife #underwaterphotography #underwaterphotos #underwaterphotographer #boatdiving #beautifulscenery #underwatershots #underwaterambience #underwaterworld #underwaterbeauty #wreck
#wreckdiving</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-12-26T03:24:30Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/BPsc43a7Kuw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>370</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/197</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/GT-rK_dnDrw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jim Atria Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review |  Pompano Beach , Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Description: The Atria is a Dutch freighter 227&apos; long and 34&apos; wide. The bow is pointed to the north and the ship is listing to the port. Her mast rise almost to 75&apos; and the wheelhouse is at 95&apos;. The Atria is engulfed in soft corals, bring a light and enjoy all the colors. Large species circle the wreck looking for an opportunity for a bait fish meal. The cargo hold is full of Glass Sweepers and Squirrel Fish

History: This Dutch built freighter, originally named Poinciana, was built in 1961. She gained notoriety after she capsized and sank in the Miami River (see above). Also if you look closely in the original photo above you can see the Empire State Building in the background. The ship was raised, towed offshore and then sunk as an artificial reef on September 23, 1987. The name was changed to honor Jim Atria, an avid diver and fisherman who played a major role in sinking the Poinciana. Originally the Jim Atria rested on her port side, until hurricane Andrew righted her in 1996</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-06-03T00:48:41Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/GT-rK_dnDrw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>316</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/392</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Od3bbebUwgc/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive Joe&apos;s Tug in Key West, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Key West has some amazing shipwrecks, when visiting Key West make sure to not only dive the Vandenburg but also Joe&apos;s Tug...enjoy the video.

Florida Keys and Key West.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2011-03-07T17:07:47Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Od3bbebUwgc</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>66</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/164</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6rViNVOAb0c/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jupiter Star Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
The 498‐ton freighter known as the Jupiter Star was launched on May 19, 1956, as the Ubbergen. She was built by B.V. v/h Scheepswerven Gebr. Van Diepen at their Waterhuizen, Netherlands, shipyard for the vessel’s first owner, the South Holland Shipping Company. The 498‐ton general cargo freighter w a s 225.9 feet long and 33.5 feet wide. In 1961, the Ubbergen was converted into alive stock carrier for the purpose of ferrying horses. With a capacity of 202 horses, over the course of five years she carried more than 50,000 horses between Amsterdam and the Baltic Sea port of Klaipéda, Lithuania. In 1966, she was retro fitted back to her original configuration of a general cargo vessel. The freighter traded hands numerous times over the next three decades: in 1968 she was sold to Peter Schaa Sr., of Leer, Germany, who renamed her the Hella Schaa; in 1976 she was sold to a Cypriot company and renamed Katerina El; she was renamed Kostas in 1979 after being sold to a Greek firm; in 1983 she was sold to the Cassandra Shipping Company and renamed the Nita II; two years later she sailed as the Pallini; in 1990 she operated as the Eleni M. for Gaya Shipping, Incorporated; a year later she was known as the Nitsa; in 1993 she was sold to a Honduran company and renamed Falcon; in 1994 she traded hands yet again and was renamed Christopher 8 Natalie; and finally, in 1994, she was sold to the Belizean shipping company Rose Shipping Limited and renamed Rosemarie. It is unclear when the vessel became known as the Jupiter Star, as this name does not appear in the vessel’s documentation history. Abandoned to rust on the Miami River, the vessel was later sold for use asan artificial reef. The Atlantic Gamefish Foundation helped prepare the freighter, which was renamed the Cleve Iones, Sr. after the founder of the Jones Boat Yard, prior to its August 14, 2002, scuttling at the Pflueger Artificial Reef Site off Miami. The former Ubbergen now rests intact on its port side, in approximately 160 feet of water. It is possible for divers with the requisite training and experience to penetrate down the funnel into the engine room, where numerous gauge panels can be observed.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-10-28T21:45:42Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rViNVOAb0c</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>179</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/85</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/GtVxLltsUeU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tracy - Ken Vitale Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Fort Lauderdale, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Description: This ship is 131&apos; long with a 32&apos; beam. The bow is pointing north and is upright. The Tracey is connected with a chain to the Jay Scutti to the south, approximately 200&apos;. The Merci Jesus lies to north. You can easily cover 2 wrecks and if the current is right you can do all 3, This area is a great dive, along with all the marine life you get to test your navigational skills.

History: The Tracey was seized by U.S. Customs for drug trafficking and towed to the Miami River where it sat derelict. Eventually the wreck sailed to Ft. Lauderdale to become an artificial reef. The ship was deployed on March 2, 1999. There is a plaque on the ship in memory of a well known local diving instructor, Ken Vitale.

Music by 

http://www.hooksounds.com
https://www.facebook.com/HookSounds</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-04-05T00:52:01Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtVxLltsUeU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>246</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/311</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6xfsgKYJlh4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>kringeline</video:title>
         <video:description>Diving the wreck of the s/v Kringeline, a 50 ft. sailing boat in 310 ft. of water about 1.5 nm east of Boca Inlet, Florida.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-10-08T19:12:46Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/6xfsgKYJlh4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>203</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/171</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Xk2QG4qgLrU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Concepcion Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review |  North Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>The Concepcion started her life in 1952 as the coastal
freighter &quot;Marie Christine&quot;.  It was 164ft long, 26ft wide,
displaced 390 tons. During its life, had several names.
In 1991, the vessel stacked with trucks, bikes,
rice, etc... was in route to Haiti when it had engine
problems, forcing them to anchor, for the last time.
On Feb 3, the weather and high seas battered
the crippled ship and it was throw up to the beach.
Sunk on June 7, 1991 as an artificial reef, at 65ft,
can be dove with the C-One and White Coast.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-04-30T13:40:41Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xk2QG4qgLrU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>150</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/3</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Bb5XLKKPAWA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Lady Luck Wreck | Sinking &amp; Diving | Pompano Beach Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Lady Luck Wreck | Sinking &amp; Diving | Pompano Beach Florida

Click here for more information on the Lady Luck Wreck: goo.gl/EyvL6A
Schedule a dive: goo.gl/GwpZUD

History of the Lady Luck Wreck:
Lady Luck, formerly known as Newtown Creek, is a 324-foot long, 49-foot wide tanker ship that was built by the Wiley Manufacturing Company in 1967.  The sludge (sewage) tanker operated in New York seven days a week while transport 1.2 million gallons of sludge per day for nearly 50 years. She was decommissioned in the summer of 2014 then sold at auction on March 1, 2016 to Shipwreck Park, Inc., a private 501 (C)(3) corporation, for $100,000.

While the sinking as slated for 2pm on July 23, 2016, it took nearly 3 hours longer than expected to sink the Lady Luck. Around 4:40pm the ship started to take on water at a faster rate. Lady Luck started to list toward her Starboard side, but managed to right herself right below the ocean&apos;s surface. While most spectator we&apos;re nervous, the five former Newtown Creek crew members who were watching from the media boat we&apos;rent concerned -- they&apos;ve seen the vessel list many times. After working on the ship for 15+ years, they knew how the sledge compartments would fill up and right itself.

Local artist Dennis MacDonald, who is known for his work on the 2015 ill-fated Rappa Nui Reef, created a mock underwater casino that includes poker tables with card sharks, an octopus dealer, mermaid cocktail waitress and over-sized dice on the Lady Luck Wreck. This dive has countless photo opportunities!

The Lady Luck Wreck&apos;s underwater casino scene is a one-of-a-kind underwater experience. 

The Lady Luck wreck will be the center focus of Shipwreck Park.

Diving The Lady Luck Wreck:
The Lady Luck is an advanced dive that rests in 131 feet off water, about a mile off shore of Atlantic Blvd. At this time there&apos;s no growth on her as she was recently sunk.  Less than 24 hours after the Lady Luck Wreck made her final voyage to the bottom of the Atlantic, spade fish started making this their new home.

Be cautious when diving the wrecks in this area. strong currents are common.

Lady Luck Wreck | Sinking &amp; Diving | Pompano Beach Florida</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-07-27T04:22:09Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bb5XLKKPAWA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>325</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/153</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ZU0P-m7ksGY/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Dive: USS Lakeland (South Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>🌊 Join us underwater as we #explore the depths of #southbeach , #Florida, and uncover the secrets of the LSM USS Lakeland. From the briefing to the #dive itself, and a journey through its rich #history, this video is a must-watch for all diving enthusiasts!

📍 *Introduction:* 0:00
Join Alejandro and ISDC as we embark on an underwater journey to explore the #deep Lakeland wreck.
📍 *Dive Brief:* 00:37  
Dive essentials and Lakeland specs: Learn about the vital information for this dive, including the dimensions and the ideal diving conditions.
📍 *The Dive Itself:* 01:33 
Descend into the depths with us as we discover the beauty of the Lakeland wreck and its marine life, right out of Governor&apos;s Cut in colorful Miami Beach.
📍 *History of the Wreck:* 04:22 
Born as the LSM-373: Uncover the history behind the Lakeland, from its origins as a vessel that served on World War II to its transformation into an artificial reef off the coast of South Beach.
📍 *Conclusion:* 05:52

Video Gear used:
- Camera: Panasonic Lumix GH6 (#panasonicgh6)  @ChannelPanasonic  
- Lights: Big Blue  @bigbluedivelights7268  
- Housing: Nauticam #nauticam 

🐠 #UnderwaterExploration #WreckDiving #PompanoBeach #RenegadeWreck #Shipwreck #DivingAdventure #OceanDiscovery #ExploreTheUnknown #ScubaDiving #underwaterhistory  #nauticam 

Don&apos;t forget to like, comment, and subscribe for more underwater adventures! Follow us on Instagram and Facebook for exclusive behind-the-scenes content. Dive deeper into the Lakeland&apos;s story with us. 🚢🔍🌊

@simplyscuba  @ScubaNation @underwatertorishorts @goldbanks119 @PanasonicLumixVideo 

*ISDC Instagram*:
www.instagram.com/internationalscubadiversclub
*ISDC Facebook*:
www.facebook.com/internationalscubadiversclub

=======================
*Edition*
Facundo Mercado Spinella
facumercadospinella@gmail.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-03-29T12:39:22Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZU0P-m7ksGY</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>390</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/53</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/M8YfZpAXzmk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Lowrance (Pompano Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Welcome to a new wreck diving video from the International Scuba Divers Club, today we present the Technical Dive on the Lowrance wreck.

Sections:
0:00 Intro
0:32 Dive Briefing
2:18 Diving the Wreck
5:58 History of the Wreck

HISTORY
Launched: 1953 as a refrigerated freighter was built by Canadian Vickers, Limited at their Montreal shipyard for the Colombian shipping company Flota Mercante Gran Colombiana SA.
1981: the mid‐ship superstructure was razed and she was converted into a barge
 
Name History:
Ciudad de Cali (1953)
Rio Amazonas (1972)
Mazon (1980)
Lowrance (1984)

Divesite:
Since its intentional sinking, the Lowrance became one of the most popular tech diving sites in all of south Florida. Named after the manufacturer of recreational marine electronics that donated funds to help sink the vessel, the Lowrance sits in approximately 200 feet of water. The hull of the former freighter provides significant vertical relief, with the main deck found at a depth of 165.
Found approximately 2.5 nautical miles outside Hillsboro Inlet, the Lowrance rests perpendicular to the generally northward‐moving Gulf Stream; even during periods of significant currents, divers usually have no problem hitting this massive target. It is also worth noting that the wreck of the Renegade is found approximately 700 feet due north of the Lowrance, should divers find themselves on the bottom and in between the two artificial reefs. The midship area is perhaps the most interesting, though the remaining upper decks have experienced significant collapse in recent years. For divers with the requisite training and experience, the wreck of the Lowrance offers a fantastic circuit through the engine room. Divers can enter through a hatch on the main deck of the vessel that leads down a hallway, eventually opening up above the engine room. Gorgonian-choked skylights above allow ambient light to trickle down onto the catwalks that line the perimeter of the room. Dropping down, divers can work their way around equipment, eventually exiting through one of several large holes cut out during the vessel’s preparation for sinking, or via a smaller hole produced by the explosive charges that sent the former freighter to the bottom.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #trek 
#biscayne #southbeach #beach #scuba #divesite</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-06-25T11:30:03Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/M8YfZpAXzmk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>478</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/360</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/n2AgYM3sY2E/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive at the Lugano Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>this is a wreck in Biscayne National Park, Homestead Florida called the SS Lugano. It is in about 30 feet water and its is home to many differant kinds of fish. This video was taken May 29 2010.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2011-08-30T01:12:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/n2AgYM3sY2E</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>133</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/128</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/k45CpCiGZf8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Army Tanks Dive,  at Mathew Lawrence Memorial Reef,  just off shore Miami Beach</video:title>
         <video:description>Two M60 Army Tanks from the Vietnam War era, 

Army Tanks is an artificial reef off the coast of Miami Beach with two M-60 Army tanks from the Vietnam War and 1060 tons of limestone rocks. Sunk by DERM in 1994 at a depth of 49 ft.,  form part of the &quot;Mathew Lawrence Memorial Reef&quot; just off shore Miami Beach.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-05-17T03:13:30Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/k45CpCiGZf8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>206</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/91</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/m_z4MIGLnI8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Merci Jesus Wreck | Scuba | Ft Lauderdale</video:title>
         <video:description>Navigating from the Jay Scutti to the Merci Jesus wreck.

The Merci Jesus is 90&apos; long and 26&apos; wide, bow pointing south and the hull is upright. A good navigator can swim from the Scutti to the Tracey then to the Merci Jesus...a trifecta! Great growth covers the ship, lots of tropical fish.

History: The Merci Jesus was seized by U.S. Customs Officials in April of 1998 for possession of drugs. The ship was then sank by the Broward County Artificial Reef Program on August 11, 1998.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-10-04T20:39:58Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/m_z4MIGLnI8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>512</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/291</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bgDqnRue9_0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jupiter Scuba Diving - MG-111</video:title>
         <video:description>The MG-111 is an old Mississippi River barge that sits in about 65 feet of water. There’s not much left of the barge other than a big rectangle area filled with steel beams and rubble. The barge itself attracts a wide variety of marine life ranging from the smallest shrimps and nudibranchs, to big goliath groupers. Just north of the barge you’ll find a bunch of columns, these were originally from the old Jupiter High school and dumped here in the ocean as an artificial reef. And that it is, there are lots of fish and critters to be found around the pillars and the sandy bottom is perfect for big stingrays. From the end of August through a part of October the Goliath Groupers like to come together over here for the grouper aggregation. We’ve seen up to 200 at a time at this site, an amazing sight! 

Book your dive today at JupiterScubaDiving.com!

The waters of Jupiter, Florida offer some of the most diverse marine life in the world.  From our Turtle Mating Season in the Spring, Goliath Grouper Aggregation during late Summer, and Lemon Shark Migration in the Winter, Jupiter scuba diving boasts large aquatic life encounters year round! We also have the smallest most colorful creatures to satisfy the macro enthusiast! If that wasn’t enough, don’t forget Manta Rays, Green Moray Eels, Southern Sting Rays, Caribbean Reef Sharks, Nurse Sharks, Hammerheads, Mola Mola and the occasional Whale Shark…we’ve got those too!

Jupiter Scuba Diving offers competitive Tank &amp; Equipment Rentals as well as Diver Training at competitive pricing. We are also a completely independent operation, opening the door for ALL shops, clubs and dive groups to utilize our awesome boat and great customer service for any and all of your needs. Our slogan sums it up:  Diving is FUN.  Expect MORE.  At Jupiter Scuba Diving / Kyalami Charters we aim to connect the dots and treat you to the ultimate Diving Experience from the moment you book until long after you return to the dock.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-06-14T21:57:24Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/bgDqnRue9_0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>85</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/101</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/zn3CAVyt4hA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Miguana (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
February 27, 2001, drug-sniffing dogs from a boarding team participating in ”Operation Riverwalk&quot; sensed cocaine near propane tanks towards the stern of the 101-foot long Miguana. A closer examination of the tanks revealed they were not properly installed and were unusually heavy.

Further scrutiny found that the tanks contained 125 pounds of cocaine worth $1.1 million.

 

Divesite:

US. Customs Reef off Miami consists of three vessels – the Brandy Wine, Etoile De Mer, and Miguana‐ scuttled in close proximity to each other, all of which were seized by the U S . Customs Service for attempting to smuggle narcotics into Florida via the Miami River. The Tacoma is also considered part of US. Customs Reef, but was sunk later and rests approximately 500 feet to the northwest of the previously‐mentioned trio.

On July 13, 2001, explosives cuttling charges sent the Miguana, a former garbage scow converted into a cargo freighter, 140 feet to the bottom of the sea.Now rests between the Brandy Wine and the Etoile de Mer, which lies west off the Miguana’s bow. The wreck of the Miguana has easy access into its interior where divers can View the former garbage scow’s engine.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-06-29T23:10:35Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/zn3CAVyt4hA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>343</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/72</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/sxTIdvkQXro/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Miller Lite Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Video Taken on a dive made September 15th 2018.


The German refrigerator cargo vessel Miller Lite was built in 1957. Her original name was Mini Horn. Later she was renamed Shirley B and then Principe Maya. She was 186 feet long, had a 29 foot beam and an eleven foot draft. After being renamed after the company that sponsored her sinking, she was sunk as an artificial reef on May 17, 1987. According to diver Ed Murphy, the Miller Light sits upright in 165 feet of water outside Hills Boro Inlet, in the Rodeo Reef Site. The interesting thing about the wreck is that it still has a life boat mounted on its davits. Remember penetration into any shipwreck should only be done by those with proper training, experience and wreck diving equipment. Scuba equipment like powerful dive lights, navigation reels, dive knives as well as redundant air supply like a pony bottle or doubles are standard gear for wreck divers. Due to her depth, this wreck should only be visited by experienced deep divers.

Description: Freighter class ship, 206&apos; long sitting upright with the bow pointing SE. Because of the ships close proximity to Hillsboro inlet it is teaming with fish. Large schools of fish are usually covering the wreckage. The ship is still fairly intact. Watch out for monofilament! Although this ship has some access at recreational limits, more advanced training is recommended.

History: This German Freighter was built in 1957 and named the Mini-horn. The ship was in service for almost 30 years and was also named the Principe Maya. In 1987 the ship was purchased by the Broward Dept. of Natural Resource Protection for $29,900. and cleaned for sinking. Funding was also donated by Miller Lite, hence the name. Among dive operators the wreck is sometimes called the &quot;Captain Mark&quot;. The ship was finally sunk on May 17, 1987</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-09-16T02:11:18Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/sxTIdvkQXro</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>235</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/112</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/wCZMZhL7JX0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>#Wreck Diving: Miss Dania Beach, a.k.a. Porte Saint Jean (Hollywood, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Miss Dania Beach, aka Porte Saint Jean Wreck Scuba Dive

Sections:
0:00 Intro
1:56 The Dive
5:17 The History

The 126-foot long Miss Dania Beach was a former Canadian Navy anti-submarine patrol vessel, which was scuttled as an artificial reef on May 29, 2004. The 210-ton vessel was sunk during Dania Beach&apos;s centennial celebration, though the reef was later dedicated to the memory of Robert E. Derecktor, a well-known local shipbuilder, whose company Derecktor Shipyards donated the vessel. The Miss Dania Beach n o w rests in 70 feet of water in close proximity to the 55-foot long former LCM Emmi Boggs, the 40-foot long former yacht Summerfield, and the tug Donal G. McAllister.

Take a look at the fascinating dive that depicts this former &quot;Porte&quot; Class Canadian Navy ship on its final resting place in Florida.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #canada #hollywood</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-09-29T13:30:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/wCZMZhL7JX0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>490</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/46</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/nTQQJpJlg0Q/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>#Wreck Diving: Miracle of Life (aka Miss Luirdies) (Boca Raton, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Welcome to another Scuba Diving video from the International Scuba Divers Club video!
Today&apos;s presentation, the shipwreck of THE MIRACLE OF LIFE

VIDEO SECTIONS
0:00 Intro
0:40 Wreck Briefing
2:19 Wreck Dive
6:25 Wreck History

HISTORY
Launched: 1972 as an off shore supply vessel by Burton Shipyard, Incorporated at Port Arthur, Texas
June 26, 2008: The freighter (Haiti) was purchased to be used use as an artificial reef after US. Customs Service agents found a steel compartment hiding ~340 pounds of cocaine during an inspection at the Port of Miami.

Name History
Safe Tide (1972)
Norpac III (1987)
Sea Bird (1999)
Miss Lourdies (2008)

Divesite:
Sunk on June 9, 2009, cargo freighter Miss Lourdies was scuttled as the “Miracle of Life” off Boca Raton. The vessel is upright and intact, with the top of the wheelhouse first encountered at a depth of 100 feet, the deck at 125 feet, and the sand at a depth 140 feet. One of the main attractions is the angel sculpture amid ship.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-02-19T11:00:15Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTQQJpJlg0Q</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>506</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/232</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/rft61zMrCqQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving Capt Tony Wreck 091519</video:title>
         <video:description>beautiful wreck and all our respect to the family of Capt Tony who lost his life to a drunk Driver.
Lots of Goliath groupers on this one.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-09-18T01:52:49Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/rft61zMrCqQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>271</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/223</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/vXpNXmMTOfY/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Castor wreck 050522</video:title>
         <video:description>Relatively shallow dive on this wreck famous for Goliath Grouper sighting. Some sharks were sighted as well on this dive.
Tech diving, decompression diving, CCR diving, South florida diving. 
Dive was out of Boynton Beach on Scubatyme charter freshly refurbished and operated by South Florida Diving Headquarters with locations in Pompano Beach and Boynton Beach, Florida.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-05-08T14:41:57Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/vXpNXmMTOfY</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>106</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/100</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/mmXjc3pDv7g/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Mystic Isle Ferry (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Mystic Isle Tec Wreck Scuba Dive | Miami, Florida

Sections
0:00 Intro
0:45 Diving the oustide
3:46 Diving the inside
6:05 Diving the history

// NOTE 1: is Passengers, not Passangers
// NOTE 2: is Seized, not Siezed

HISTORY
Launched: 1942 as a car/passenger ferry by the Burger Boat Company of Manitowoc, Wisconsin.

The first all ‐steel, all‐welded passenger boat of its kind on the Great Lakes, she was built to replace the Erie Island Ferry Company’s vessel Erie Isle on the run between Catawba Island, Put-In-Bay, and Middle Bass.

Had room onbard for 335 passangers and 20 cars.

1950: Sold to the Fishers Island Ferry District of New York.

1978: traded to the Blount Marine Corporation of Warren, Rhode Island

July 1979: sold to Donald Marshall of Fort Lauderdale, so The Mystic Isle arrived in Florida

Late 1979: sold to Starboard Navigation Company of Panama, who converted her into a fishing vessel.

June 2nd, 1984: U.S.C.G.C. Diligence seized the Mystic Isle about 100 miles northeast of Miami when she was found carrying a load of marijuana.

 

Divesite:

The wreck of the Mystic Isle sits upright and intact off Virginia Key. The small wreck is easy to penetrate through the large automobile opening in her hull just below the wheelhouse. Just off the stern and to the north of the wreck rests the yacht Esmeralda. It is possible for experienced divers to visit both wrecks on the same dive should they be using scooters or if a swift, north current is running.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #ferry</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-09-22T02:02:54Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/mmXjc3pDv7g</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>444</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/172</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/8WjOs-nP5ps/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Narwal Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | North Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>This video is about scuba diving the Narwal Wreck.

Narwal was a coaster built in the Netherlands
and launched on June 5th, 1939.  Weighted
291 tons with 136 ft length and 25 ft beam.

Sunk on April 17th, 1986 rests in 125 ft of water. It 
used to be in perfect shape until hurricane Andrew
cut it in half and torn apart the center section.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-04-17T18:10:22Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/8WjOs-nP5ps</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>143</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/245</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/3r4TZ-N3ThQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Northern Lights Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>@divesoft_tv
#gopro11</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-06-02T20:04:37Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/3r4TZ-N3ThQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>107</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/90</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/tlNYTpVrBFA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dixie Divers Presents Noula Express Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-05-19T19:52:43Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/tlNYTpVrBFA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>266</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/43</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/fn_5KHGSqLA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>VR360 - Okinawa Wreck in Pompano Beach, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>Dive the Okinawa wreck in Pompano Beach, FL. One of the newest wrecks in southeast Florida, the Okinawa offers a great experience for every diver. Wreck penetration ONLY with the right certifications and experience.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-04-24T19:25:08Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/fn_5KHGSqLA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>1043</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/154</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/C9mf55eno-w/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Orion Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Originally named the Trinidad when built in 1928 for the Panama Canal Company, this tug was brought to Miami in the 1970&apos;s and used as a diesel mechanics school. She was sunk in December of 1981 as part of the Key Biscayne Artificial Reef Program. The Orion is now one of Miami&apos;s most frequented dive sites.

This 120 foot steel tug sits upright and intact in 95 feet of water with a slight starboard tilt. The Orion&apos;s ten foot propeller and twin sets of engines have remained intact, while her stacks rise 30 feet, her intact wheel house and superstructure make this wreck a great site for underwater photography.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-01-28T02:08:05Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/C9mf55eno-w</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>199</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/99</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/DA2z0rhuvWw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>#Wreck Diving: Paraiso III (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>This is the scuba diving guide for the wreck of the Paraiso III in Miami, Florida.

Sections:
0:00 Intro
0:35 Dive Briefing
2:30 The Dive

Little is known about this vessel’s construction and/or service history, though it appears she was built as an offshore supply vessel. The Paraiso III now rests in 75 feet of water between the Rio Miami and Princess Britney.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #trek 
#biscayne #southbeach #beach #scuba #divesite</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-03-12T17:00:15Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/DA2z0rhuvWw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>365</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/132</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/2ZL386_uOo8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Miss Patricia Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>The Patricia is a steel tug that was sunk in 1990. The tug is mostly intact with a profile rising 20 feet from the sandy bottom at 53 feet. This wreck is only 100 feet from the Karline.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-10-07T20:05:05Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/2ZL386_uOo8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>120</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/408</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/qxOWGVtdAX0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Peter McAllister Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>Scuba Diving Fort Lauderdale, Florida. Peter McAllister Wreck. Tugboat in 70 deep.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-03-03T23:50:40Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/qxOWGVtdAX0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>107</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/263</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/xHJFIcki-ZU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Scuba Diving the Princess Anne Wreck in Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>PRINCESS ANNE WRECK
Average Depth: 80 ft. / 24 m 

Max Depth: 100 ft. / 30 m 


The Princess Anne is a 350 foot car ferry, once used to carry over 200 passengers and cars over the Chesapeake Bay, was sunk in the early 1990’s.

The vessel sits upright with her stern sitting in 105 feet of water and her bow in 95 feet of water. The hull begins at 100 feet of water and rises up to 72 feet. An excellent multilevel dive profile was created when a storm separated the wheelhouse from the main ship and set it beside the hull, increasing the Anne’s complexity, and attracting more marine life in the process. Because of this, one person can visibly shake the 350 ft. long 58 ft. wide and 52 ft. tall ferry, thus penetration is allowed for this reason.

Nestled near a beautiful reef system, those who are not trained in wreck diving have plenty to see outside of the ship. Schools of jacks, barracuda, parrotfish, Atlantic spadefish and the occasional shark swim through the surrounding waters and corals cover the structure of the wreck. Trained wreck divers can explore open rooms, some over 100′ in length, intact staircases, and other parts of the ship. Divers often have a seat at the marine head for a photo or a rest break.

This site is less traveled because of the 100′ depth and unstable positioning, making it an experienced diver only site. Although it has only been in the water a short time, the wreck has already established itself as one of the best wreck dives in the United States, despite being considered as the biggest and toughest wreck dive in the Palm Beach area in the non-technical class due to its usually swift current.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-05-05T20:36:09Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/xHJFIcki-ZU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>120</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/32</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Lvi1rdvMZFc/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>#Wreck Diving: Princess Britney (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Sections:
0:00 Intro
0:32 Dive Briefing
2:37 The Dive
6:25 History of the Wreck

HISTORY
Launched: July 10, 1956, as a cargo vessel by Nobiskrug Werft of Rendsburg, Germany and owned by Captain Behrens.

1965: owned by Martin von Ronn
1973: owned by Giromar Shipping Company, Limited of Cyprus
1973: owned by Eva Sorensen, Denmark
1975: owned by Harry Jacobsen
1998: owned by Leyenda Shipping, Incorporated of Belize
2001: owned by Salvador Shipping and Trading of El Salvador
2002: seized by the US. Customs after 156 pounds of cocaine were discovered hidden underneath the deck in the freighter’s engine room during ”Operation Riverwalk.”
Sunk: April 29, 2003

Name History
Heinz Helmut (1956)
Elbstrand (or Elbestrand) (1965)
Claudia (1973)
Ellen Peter (1973)
Lorelei (1975)
Leyenda (1998)
Princess Britney (2001)

Divesite

Divers will find the Princess Britney upright and intact, and in close proximity to several other artificial reefs. Several swim-thrus are available at the wreck, including the visit of a pretty intact engine room and the quarters.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k #trek 
#biscayne #southbeach #beach #scuba #divesite</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-04-01T04:00:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lvi1rdvMZFc</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>537</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/40</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/G8N1vj8mHlU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Captain Dan and Quallman Tugs</video:title>
         <video:description>Had two fun dives on Scubatyme Scuba Charters.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-02-07T14:34:50Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/G8N1vj8mHlU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>63</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/247</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/XBlIfIlHfWk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Queen of Nassau wreck 05/10/21</video:title>
         <video:description>Built in England in 1904, this was a 200 foot long Canadian vessel with a 25 foot beam. ... Stationed out of Halifax, Nova Scotia, she was considered the fastest vessel in the CFPS. She became their flagship and was responsible for protecting Canada&apos;s fishing interests. she now rests in 220Ft of sea water out of Islamorada key in Florida.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-05-19T19:24:38Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/XBlIfIlHfWk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>181</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/222</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/4ZmTXnID2ZU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Rapa Nui Reef | Sinking + Scuba Diving Rapa Nui Reef | Deerfield Beach</video:title>
         <video:description>Rapa Nui Reef | Sinking + Scuba Diving Rapa Nui Reef | Deerfield Beach

Rapa Nui Reef floated 70&apos; above its final resting place. The tugboat&apos;s horn blew and the barge slowly started to sink into the Atlantic off the coast of Deerfield Beach. everyone was excited. A new reef to scuba dive in South Florida. 

Excitement slowly turned into sadness when one of the barge&apos;s corner started sinking faster than the others. Soon the whole edge is submerged as the south edge slowly rises out of the water then makes it&apos;s way into the ocean in a vertical motion. Silence. people are shocked of what just happened. 

Did it right it&apos;s self? It&apos;s too soon to tell. 

30 minutes later, over the radio it was announced, &quot;Rapa Nui Reef is upside down.&quot;

Everyone was shocked. Rapa Nui Reef. The one of a kind reef did not go as planned. 

----- Scuba Diving Rapa Nui Reef -----

A giant stride off Pompano Dive Center&apos;s Sea Siren into the Atlantic. As we slowly descended the tag line. What condition will the Rapa Nui Reef be in was on everyone&apos;s mind. Will the sculptures be scattered around the barge?

With 20 foot visibility, we approached a rusty, rectangular object. No signs of Rapa Nui Reef. We reach the sand. Slowly fighting the current to see what&apos;s beneath the barge, no one was able to clearly define what we were looking at. We all knew we were looking at sadness. A major upset to the South Florida dive community. 

As we made our way around the barge, pieces of the Rapa Nui Reef broke off and were scattered. Re-bar&apos;s was exposed and Rusty water spewed out of the barge as it continued to settle.

No one went below Rapa Nui Reef as it was not safe.. 

Rapa Nui Reef reached its final resting place 3 hours ago and we were among the first scuba divers to see it underwater. 

It&apos;s sad sight which resulted from only the best intentions. We will remember the Rapa Nui Reef the way it was at The Cove 48 hours before. 

A personal, special thanks goes out to the excellent team at Pompano Dive Center. http://www.PompanoDive.com

Rapa Nui Reef | Sinking + Scuba Diving Rapa Nui Reef | Deerfield Beach</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-06-09T03:17:21Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZmTXnID2ZU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>153</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/165</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/orOPHW63blE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Raychel Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Raychel Wreck

On October 18th, 1990, the Raychel cleared Government Cut and was prepairing to turn southbound at the seaward end of the shipping channel, for the Truks and Caicos Islands.

On this trip, she was burdened with a cargo of cinder blocks, lumber, eight vehicles and eight cargo containers.

Captain Ray Minor had just taken over the helm from the harbor pilot, who departed the ship near the channel marker number 2.  With winds blowing approximately 20 miles per hour, the pilot boat pulled away from the lee side of the freighter and was 300ft away when the cargo apparently shifted.  The Raychel quickly took on a list and began to capsize.  While the crew escaped unharmed, the Raychel settled on her side at 43 ft of water.

The Raychel remained on the shipping channel for several months until the cargo was either salvaged or looted (many crates of Jack Daniels where onboard, catching particular interest from local divers).  Later, the freighter was raised in several large sections and taken via barge to her final resting spot.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-03-17T23:18:41Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/orOPHW63blE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>219</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/202</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/MhkTuqcCtyk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Dive: Renegade (Pompano Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>🌊 Join us underwater as we #explore the depths of #pompanobeach , #Florida, and uncover the secrets of the cargo ship Renegade. From the briefing to the #dive itself, and a journey through its rich #history, this video is a must-watch for all diving enthusiasts!

📍 *Introduction:* 0:00
Join Alejandro and ISDC as we embark on an underwater journey to explore the #deep Renegade wreck.
📍 *Dive Brief:* 00:38  
Dive essentials and Renegade specs: Learn about the vital information for this dive, including the dimensions of the Renegade and the ideal diving conditions.
📍 *The Dive Itself:* 01:36 
Descend into the depths with us as we discover the beauty of the Renegade wreck and its marine life.
📍 *History of the Wreck:* 03:53 
From The Capri to the Renegade: Uncover the history behind the Renegade, from its origins as The Capri to its transformation into an artificial reef off the coast of Pompano Beach.
📍 *Conclusion:* 04:44

Video Gear used:
- Camera: Panasonic Lumix GH6 (#panasonicgh6) @ChannelPanasonic 
- Lights: Big Blue @bigbluedivelights7268 
- Housing: Nauticam #nauticam 

🐠 #UnderwaterExploration #WreckDiving #PompanoBeach #RenegadeWreck #Shipwreck #DivingAdventure #OceanDiscovery #ExploreTheUnknown #ScubaDiving #underwaterhistory  #nauticam 

Don&apos;t forget to like, comment, and subscribe for more underwater adventures! Follow us on Instagram and Facebook for exclusive behind-the-scenes content. Dive deeper into the Renegade&apos;s story with us. 🚢🔍🌊

@simplyscuba @DubaiDiver @ScubaNation @PADIProTV @underwatertorishorts @goldbanks119 @PanasonicLumixVideo  

www.instagram.com/internationalscubadiversclub
www.facebook.com/internationalscubadiversclub</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-02-22T20:31:57Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/MhkTuqcCtyk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>316</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/162</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/4pItL3-Vv2Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Rex Bear (aka Augie Ferrigno) Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Also known as the M/V Augie Ferrigno, this 273&apos; steel coastal freighter was sunk in 1998 and she lies on the seabed upright and intact with 80’ of relief. Considering her age, the ship is in great condition with little signs of breakdown or collapse. She has very little in the way of coral growth other than general encrustation. With her superstructure intact, there’s plenty of opportunities for penetration for those with the proper training and equipment. The skylights aft of the superstructure allow entrance into the engine room. Her deck work areas are still full of winches, windlasses and other deck gear. Her mast is lying down and hanging over the rails, football-style goalposts rise from her deck and the cargo holds are cavernous There’s a lot to explore on just one dive and a little mystery makes for some desire to return. There is some evidence of fishing on the wreck but nowhere near the extent commonly noted. This is a particularly large and impressive wreck, certainly one of the most interesting sites off Miami below 200 feet.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-04-28T02:47:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/4pItL3-Vv2Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>232</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/35</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/SCUH9xZ4qqM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Robert Edmister Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>This 95 foot Coast Guard cutter was built in 1953 and was resold at in auction in Fort Lauderdale to a businessman who renamed her Robert Edmister after a friend who had passed away. The newly named Robert Edmister was sunk on Dec. 11, 1989 and sits upright in 70 feet of water. The Edmister has already attracted a good variety of marine life including coral. For the wreck diver, the pilothouse and cargo hold can be penetrated. 

QUICK FACTS:

Type: Wreck
Min. Depth: 60ft. / 18m
Max. Depth: 70 ft. / 21m
Skill Level: Advanced Open Water Diver</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-10-20T22:43:55Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/SCUH9xZ4qqM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>51</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/75</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/yO9B7zXiH-g/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Rodeo 25 Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>RODEO 25
On June 19, 1956, the Rodeo 25 was launched as the Nore (IMO number 5225909) by Scheepsbouw Unie N. V. at Groningen, Netherlands. The new coaster was 214.7 feet long, 32.5 feet wide, displaced 495 tons gross, and was powered by a Klockner Humboldt Deutz diesel engine. In 1969 the freighter was sold to William Coe and Company, Limited of Bridgetown, England, and renamed Booker Trojan. She was renamed Caricom Adventurer upon her sale to St. Godric’s Shipping Company, Limited of Limassol, Cyprus in 1976. Later that same year, she was acquired by Carigulf Lines of Panama and operated as Carigulf Venture. Finally, in 1986, the freighter sailed as Windward Trader for Windward Shipping Corporation of Honduras. In 1990, the Honduran owners of the Windward Trader faced financial problems, forcing the sale of the freighter to the Pompano Beach Fishing Rodeo, which subsequently renamed her Rodeo 25 in recognition of the Rodeo’s 25th anniversary. The vessel was cleaned and sunk as an artificial reef in 130 feet of water off Fort Lauderdale on May 12, 1990, approximately 500 feet south of the tug Mary St. Phillip (Mariner II). Since her scuttling, the Rodeo 25 has been impacted by numerous storms. The wreck lists significantly to starboard with her bow almost over on her side, and the hull forward of her stern superstructure is collapsing. Colorfully decorated with the invasive orange cupcoral, the Rodeo 25 typically hosts abundant marine life and offers an enjoyable diving experience.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-05T00:28:01Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/yO9B7zXiH-g</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>175</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/44</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/drXOgGWLcFg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Montaje: Naufragios RBJ &amp; Chris and Corey (75 metros) - Florida, USA</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-06-14T12:39:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/drXOgGWLcFg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>114</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/173</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/MMoAsWTethw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Rossmerry wreck 102713</video:title>
         <video:description>260Ft deep wreck full of lionfish</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2013-11-02T01:54:52Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/MMoAsWTethw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>95</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/42</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/niAa9LDzWy8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>RSB-1 Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>This video is about RSB-1

Description: The RSB-1 is a 160&apos; long tender. The bow is pointing to north and the ship is upright. This is another ship with tall structure on the wheel house, creating a great fish haven. Usually you will see schools of fish around the mast, Penetrating the ships hold is very easy thru large openings.

History: The RSB-1 was built in 1966 and was used as an oil company tender. In 1971 it was purchased by the Navy. She eventually wound up with the Pompano Fishing Rodeo and Broward County Artificial Reef Program. The RSB-1 was renamed the JIm Torgerson, after the lead explosive expert with the Broward County Sherriff&apos;s. The Jim Togerson was deployed April 23, 1994.

Music by HookSounds:
http://www.hooksounds.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-03-31T18:24:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/niAa9LDzWy8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>160</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/88</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/W-GiI0Qp72M/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Sea Emperor Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Description: The Sea Emperor was a hopper barge 171&apos; long and 45&apos; wide. The barge is upside down with the bow pointing to the south. Inside the wreck and to the east lie 1600 tons of concrete drainage culverts. The barge is also home to Goliath Groupers, eels, stingrays, nurse sharks and hundreds of other fish. This is a photographer&apos;s paradise! Penetration in this wreck is safe. There is light and access to surface in every chamber. This dive site has been featured in numerous magazines and T.V. shows worldwide. The Sea Emperor is part of a 3 wreck triangle. The United Caribbean lies to the SE and can be reached by following the limestone bolders placed in a row (yellow brick road). The Noulla Express lies to the East, however it is a little trickier to reach in a single dive.

History: The Sea Emperor was formerly a hopper barge that was donated as part of a fine levied on a dredging company that destroyed some reef habitat off Palm Beach County. She was filled with large concrete culverts and then sunk of Boca Raton. When the barge sank it flipped, scattering the culverts and landing upside down creating a fantastic playground for fish and divers alike.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-08-12T21:06:15Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/W-GiI0Qp72M</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>170</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/289</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/wDXyuMyY3_Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Sea Mist in Jupiter 102319</video:title>
         <video:description>deep dive in 220FSW Built in Stockholm Sweden in 1965, was sunk as a reef in 2001, 2353 gross ton, one diesel engine, one screw</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-10-24T00:44:40Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/wDXyuMyY3_Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>283</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/108</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/X8Dh80Odiu4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Sheri Lyn Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>SHERI LYN Miami

The Sheri Lyn was a 235 foot long steel passenger freighter sunk on June 18, 1987, as an artificial reef. Captain Joel Auerbach was with one of the first group of divers to visit the wreck. Mirach-N on the starboard side of her bow. This was her original name. After some research, Joel learned that she was built in Holland in 1952 and was powered by an 1100 hp Werkspoor diesel engine. The wreck now lies fully intact in 95 feet of water in the Key Biscayne reef area. The Sheri Lynn rises to within 45 feet of the surface.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-11-10T20:47:49Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/X8Dh80Odiu4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>148</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/411</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/NKHsXhiadCg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Buceando el Simbad - Mar del Plata, Argentina</video:title>
         <video:description>En esta edición especial de Buceando Ando viajamos a Mar del Plata, en Argentina, para bucear el nuevo arrecife artificial del Simbad.
Pero no solo les mostraremos la inmersión, también les contamos como fue el proceso de hundimiento y qué se puede esperar del arrecife en términos de desarrollo ecológico.

No se olviden de visitar el canal de Alfredo Elena: www.youtube.com/payelena

Las Partes del video:
0:00 Intro
2:05 Hundiendo al Simbad
5:40 Buceando en Mar del Plata
6:57 Buceando el Simbad
10:44 Bitácora de la inmersión
11:10 Arrecifes Artificiales desde el punto de vista ecológico
17:29 Agradecimientos y cierre

#buceo #naufragio #wreck #wreckdiving #mardelplata #4k #scuba #scubadiving #underwater</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-09-08T11:25:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/NKHsXhiadCg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>1127</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/175</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/MC8r-VhDDXw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Sir Scott (Miami, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>0:00 Intro
0:39 The Divesite Facts
1:37 The Dive
5:09 The History

In April and May 1958, Naviera Lagos received the ships “Lago Isoba” and “Lago Enol”, which were the first with which it began its journey under the naval credit provided by the Merchant Marine Law of 1956. Both were built at the Euskalduna shipyard, these were to be followed by the ships &quot;Lago Como&quot;, &quot;Lago Garda&quot;, &quot;Lago Mar&quot;, &quot;Lago Mayor&quot;, &quot;Lago Sanabria&quot;, &quot;Lago Ercina&quot;, &quot;Lago Negro&quot; and &quot;Lago San Mauricio ”.

Until the beginning in 1964 of the joint operations between Naviera Lagos and Naviera Pinillos, the seafaring life of the ship “Lago Isoba” was spent on tramp trips dedicated mainly to transporting wood from northern Europe. From then on, she moved to the fruit line between the Canary Islands and the Peninsula with palletized loads and in the course of 1969 she made two extraordinary trips to the port of Guayaquil, Ecuador, carrying locomotives and various railway equipment for that country.

In 1974 the ships &quot;Lago Isoba&quot; and &quot;Lago Enol&quot; were acquired by Naviera Alvargonzález, from Gijón, whose password was renamed &quot;Labrador&quot; and &quot;Troubadour&quot; as of 1976, respectively. By then they had been converted into mini-bulk carriers and both continued in tramp traffic, although our protagonist was sold that same year to the Panamanian company Naviera Peninsular and renamed &quot;Azuero Dos&quot;.

In 1978 it went on to fly the Greek flag and the password of the Sanroc Co. International company renamed &quot;Atlantis III&quot;. A year later it appeared under the name of Naviera Atlantis, management of Venisa Liner and renamed &quot;Atlantis V&quot; and in 1980, when it was acquired by Scott Line, it became the management of River Shipping Corp., flagged in Panama with the new name of &quot; Sir Scott ”, until its intentional sinking in 1985 as an artificial reef, near Miami (USA).

Of 1,556 gross tons, 1,030 net tons and 2,408 deadweight tons, in a hull of 76.36 m of total length -70.29 m of length between perpendiculars-, 11.36 m of beam, 7.10 m of depth and a depth of 5.71 m. It was powered by a Naval Polar M48M diesel engine, manufactured under license in the La Naval workshops in Sestao, with 1,480 horsepower on a shaft and cooled by salt water - a reason for frequent maintenance problems -, which allowed it to maintain a speed of 12 knots. IMO code 5202134.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-10-17T03:02:31Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/MC8r-VhDDXw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>474</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/64</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/2jxF-6wnaZM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Skycliff (Boynton Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>#Dive with us the Skycliff wreck off the coast of Boynton Beach, Florida! From the dive briefing to the heart-pounding exploration and the intriguing history, this underwater adventure has it all. Subscribe now for more captivating dives and oceanic discoveries! 🐠🌊

📍 *Introduction:* 0:00
🚀 Dive into Adventure: Join us on a thrilling journey as Alejandro introduces the mesmerizing Skycliff wreck and sets the stage for our upcoming dive briefing. 🌟

📍 *Dive Briefing:* 0:46
🗺️ Location, depth, and dimensions of the Skycliff wreck
 Notable features, including intact superstructure and access points for penetration

📍 *the Dive:* 2:15
 🐟 Into the Depths: Join Alejandro and the ISDC team as they navigate through strong currents, seeking shelter among the wreck&apos;s superstructure, and witnessing the vibrant marine life. 🌊
Encounters with marine life
Navigating through the wreck&apos;s structure

📍 *History of the Wreck:* 6:20
📜 Unveiling History: Explore the backstory of the Skycliff wreck, from its construction in 1961 to its transformation into an artificial reef in 1991. 🚢
 
📍 *Conclusion:* 7:17
 🎬 Wrapping Up: Reflecting on the adventure, Alejandro shares final thoughts on the exploration of the Skycliff wreck and invites viewers to join us for future underwater escapades.

Join us in unraveling the secrets of the Skycliff wreck! Leave a comment below with your thoughts and dive stories. Like, share, and dive deeper into the adventure! 🌊🚢 #SkycliffWreck #UnderwaterExploration #ScubaDiving #Shipwreck #OceanAdventures #ExploreTheUnknown

@ExploreOceans @DiversReady @InternationalScubaDiversClub @Tdisdi @CNN @HISTORY @DiscoveryLAT@discovery @PADIProTV</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-01-29T13:57:33Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/2jxF-6wnaZM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>476</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/5</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/GCgMBgooBJQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Montaje: Penetración en Naufragio Spiegel Grove (40 metros) - Florida, USA</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-06-14T12:39:06Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/GCgMBgooBJQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>126</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/49</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/JEzW0o1d4Oc/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>SS Copenhagen Shipwreck</video:title>
         <video:description>https://www.lauderdalebythesea-fl.gov/232/SS-Copenhagen</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-07-12T23:36:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/JEzW0o1d4Oc</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>354</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/84</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/DisnWRdDrsQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Star Trek Wreck Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>USS STAR TREK (210’) This 200&apos; Landing Ship Medium (LSM) was sunk in 1982 and has 32’ of relief. She lies on her starboard side and her hull is bent about one-third of the way back from the bow. Unlike her sister ships the Lakeland and the Pioneer One, also sunk off Miami, the Star Trek&apos;s superstructure was extensively modified from her wartime configuration. The years have not been kind to the Star Trek; the modified bridge and superstructure were badly damaged in Hurricane Andrew and now lie mostly destroyed in the sand beneath the wreck. She also had aircraft carrier like external walkways installed on both sides to allow the crew to traverse the ship without entering the cargo holds, however the external walkway on the port (top) side has begun to fall off making for an interesting swim through. About the only interesting original features left intact are the guarded props. Some penetration is possible (she has many dark silty internal passages) but probably inadvisable in her deteriorating state. Given her age there was surprisingly little coral growing on her.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-02-03T05:02:58Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/DisnWRdDrsQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>201</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/76</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/UHf3pqR6eo8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Sucre (Pompano Beach, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>Welcome to another International Scuba Divers Club video!
Today&apos;s presentation, THE SUCRE

VIDEO SECTIONS
0:00 Intro
0:47 Wreck Facts
1:55 Wreck Dive
5:18 Wreck History

HISTORY
Launched: April 2, 1957, as a freighter at the Bremerhaven, Germany shipyard Schiflbaugesellschafl Unterweser A.G.
Sold on 1980 and 1988
1991: Sold to Honduran owners
1994: Siezed by the US. Coast Guard after finding 300 pounds of cocaine onboard

Name History:
Louise (1957)
Chiloe III (1980)
Kenco l (1988)
Sucre (1991)
 
Divesite:
The freighter rests upright and intact in approximately 215 feet of water, with the main deck encountered at 190 feet. The forward portion of the vessel consists of two large vacant holds, each with its own cargo crane on deck that affords an interesting photo opportunity, while the aft superstructure and engine room allows for some interesting exploration. The forward bridge bulk heads have collapsed, which has produced an odd vacant area surrounded on each side by the intact bridge wings. The bow pointing south ward.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #caribbean #rebreather #ccr
#underwatervideo #sea #travel #wreckdiving #penetration #sidemount
#tecdiving #wreck #dive #Florida #infographic #briefing #rust #4k</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-12-04T16:00:11Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/UHf3pqR6eo8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>416</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/152</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/jPRr1eDw3uQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Etoile de Mer &amp; Tacoma Wreck</video:title>
         <video:description>Deco Divers
Miami Beach, FL
5/25/2015

GoPro $ Black
Dual Sola video lights</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-05-27T02:09:56Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/jPRr1eDw3uQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>208</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/374</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/19LOwYUImRI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>BuceandoAndo 15: Naufragio Thunderbolt (35 metros) -  Marathon, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>En este episodio de Buceando Ando, nos vamos al arrecife artificial del Thunderbolt, un barco de cableado submarino en el Cayo Marathon!
Las partes del video:

0:00 Intro
1:01 En el Barco
1:53 La Inmersión
4:37 La Bitacora</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-08-02T12:55:56Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/19LOwYUImRI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>378</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/146</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Bh3OYxkV4Bs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tortuga Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | South Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Sunk on April 25th, 1995, during the climax of the movie &quot;Fair Game&quot;, the Tortuga rests now in 110 ft of water off Miami.
With a total length of 165 feet, the wreck offers lots of opportunity for penetration.  Of course to explore these spaces the diver needs to be trained to do so.

Hundido el 25 de Abril de 1995, durante el climax del film &quot;Fair Game&quot;,  el Tortuga descansa hoy en 30 m de profundidad.
Con una longitud total de 50 m, el pecio ofrece mucha oportunidad para penetración.  Desde ya que a fin de explorar estos espacios, el buceador debe estar debidamente entrenado.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-04-14T12:46:04Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bh3OYxkV4Bs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>251</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/189</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/uODzWwYDOMA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Dive: Tracor DryDocks (Fort Lauderdale, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>🌊 Join us underwater as we #explore the depths of #fortlauderdale  , #florida , for a great dive on the Tracor Dry Docks. From the briefing to the #dive itself, and a glimpse of its #history, you can&apos;t miss this video in 4k!

📍 *Introduction:* 0:00
Join Alejandro and ISDC as we embark on an underwater journey to explore the #deep sunken Dry Dock.
📍 *Dive Brief:* 00:40
Dive essentials and Dry Docks specs: Learn about the vital information for this dive, including the dimensions and the ideal diving conditions.
📍 *The Dive Itself:* 01:40
Descend into the depths with us to the depth and uncover the wreck and its marine life, right out of Port Everglades.
📍 *History of the Wreck:* 06:43
Learn a bit about the history of this Dry Dock.
📍 *Conclusion:* 07:17

Video Gear used:
- Camera: Panasonic Lumix GH6 (#panasonicgh6)   @ChannelPanasonic   
- Lights: Big Blue  @bigbluedivelights7268  
- Housing: Nauticam #nauticam 

🐠 #UnderwaterExploration #WreckDiving #PompanoBeach #RenegadeWreck #Shipwreck #DivingAdventure #OceanDiscovery #ExploreTheUnknown #ScubaDiving #underwaterhistory  #nauticam 

Don&apos;t forget to like, comment, and subscribe for more underwater adventures! Follow us on Instagram and Facebook for exclusive behind-the-scenes content. Dive deeper into the Dry Dock&apos;s story with us. 🚢🔍🌊

*ISDC Instagram*:
www.instagram.com/internationalscubadiversclub
*ISDC Facebook*:
www.facebook.com/internationalscubadiversclub

=======================
*Edition*
Facundo Mercado Spinella
facumercadospinella@gmail.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-04-08T13:00:06Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/uODzWwYDOMA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>468</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/193</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Iwy47jyTNJg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tec #Wreck Diving: Trio Bravo Tug (Fort Lauderdale, Florida)</video:title>
         <video:description>On this video the International Scuba Divers Club brings you the TRIO BRAVO Wreck.

The sections:
0:00 Intro
0:42 Dive Briefing
2:05 The Dive on the Wreck
5:12 The History of the Wreck

HISTORY
Launched 1898 by the Columbia Iron Works and Drydock Company in Baltimore, Maryland for the Consolidated Coal Company as one of their tugboats.
1950: Sold to The Roen Steamship Company and worked the Great Lakes.
1980: Sold to Trio Shipping Company of Honduras
January 21, 1981: Trio Bravo sank at her dock in Port Everglades, and remained submerged until March 14
August 1981: was offered at auction and later prepared for disposal as an artificial reef
December 16, 1983: Sunk in Fort Lauderdale

Name History
Cumberland (1898)
John Roen V (1950)
Trio Bravo (1980)

Divesite:
The Trio Bravo now sits upright and intact, with its superstructure being significantly impacted from the explosions that sunk it. Also, there is quite a nice opening for access to the vessel’s interior, and divers can easily swim down into the engine room to observe the large boilers resting in her belly, as well as other adjacent compartments.

#diving #scubadiving #ocean #underwater #underwatervideo #sea
#travel #wreckdiving #tecdiving #wreck #dive</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-02-26T15:00:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iwy47jyTNJg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>455</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/160</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/NUSIYPO_ogw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Ultra Freeze Wreck Scuba Dive | Miami Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>HISTORY
Launched: 1959, at the Hamburg, Germany shipyard of J.J Siet as Schifiwerfl for Heinrich C. Horn , the same original owner of the Mimi Horn (Miller Lite) as a refrigerated freighter

1965: sold to the Hamburg South American Line

1968: sold to United Trans-Caribbean Navigation, Incorporated of Panama

1970: sold

1983: sold to Carpentaria SA. of Panama

September 1983: Following her sale to Carpentaria S.A., a survey in Guayaquil, Ecuador found the Ultra Freeze to be in dramatically poor condition. The owners ignored the findings though, and had the freighter loaded with a cargo of 200 tons of shrimp and set sail for Miami

December 16, 1983: En route, the Ultra Freeze was forced to dock at Panama for repairs, which delayed the vessel for several months even though the repairs were apparently never completed. The reefer was finally towed into Miami on with a cargo of badly decomposing shrimp, representing a loss of over $1.5 million worth of product.

 

Name History:

Herbert Horn (1959)

Mary B (1968)

Ultra Freeze (1970)

 

Divesite:

The Ultra Freeze, now resting in approximately 120 feet, is a large and impressive wreck. In 1992, Hurricane Andrew ripped the starboard side of the hull open, bent the hull 90 degrees at amidships, and stripped the pilothouse from the hull. There is extensive penetration possible, but divers should have the requisite experience before exploring the interior due to fallen electrical cables and general deterioration. Unfortunately, the Ultra Freeze rests in an area that apparently is subject to chronically turbid visibility.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-03-29T00:30:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/NUSIYPO_ogw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>224</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/205</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6J_1JcPye6U/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Union Express Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Description: The Union Express is a 170&apos; long Dutch Coastal Freighter. The ship is laying on the port side, broken in 2 pieces, facing north. The Mariner II Barge is just offshore to ENE in swimming distance. The Union Express is part of the &quot;Wreck Graveyard&quot;. There are 7 wrecks within 1000&apos; of each other. Large schools of fish followed by large pelagics swim between the wrecks.

History: The Union Express was built in Germany in 1959. Designed as a coastal freighter, the ship worked for awhile in the Northern Sea and later carried food and supplies in the Caribbean and down the South American coast. The ship was seized by Federal Agents in 1990 for drug smuggling. Finally on April 25, 1992 she was sunk by the Pompano Fishing Rodeo and the Broward County Artificial Reef Program. She is sometimes called the Outboard Mariner 1 due to sponsorship money donated by a engine manufacturer.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-10-10T00:17:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/6J_1JcPye6U</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>189</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/89</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/640QMAWz0qI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>United Caribbean Wreck Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Pompano Beach, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>Description: The Caribbean is a steel cargo ship 147&apos; long. The bow points to the SE. Off the stern limerock boulders were placed in a line leading divers to and from the wreck of the Sea Emperor 250&apos; to the NE. The Caribbean is one of the wrecks in the wreck triangle. Because of the close proximity to two other wrecks and a reef, it populated very quickly. Many of the same marine residents that occupy the Emperor can be seen on the Caribbean. The wreck moved slightly and sustained some damage during hurricane Wilma.

History: The ship was built in 1969 and named the Golden Venture. It was registered Panamanian to operate only in waters around Singapore. But by the early 1990&apos;s, it was being used by smugglers to illegally ferry people and drugs. On June 6, 1993 the Golden Venture ran aground on Rockaway Beach in Queens New York. The ship was smuggling 286 illegal immigrants from China. In their attempts to flee the stranded ship and get to shore in the United States, ten people drowned. The ship was later sold and renamed the United Caribbean and was used a s a cargo vessel in the Caribbean. The ship eventually became part of the Palm Beach Artificial Reef Program and was sunk on August 22, 2000. There are several movies chronicling the horrifying journey of the 286 immigrants</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-08-05T22:04:07Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/640QMAWz0qI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>144</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/403</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/S_cSKkEVBkw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Underwater Technological Services - ROV footage of the shipwreck  USS Amesbury near Key West, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>In Feb of 2008 U.T.S. used a VideoRay Pro 3 ROV to document a WWII destroyer that sank west of Key West, FL.  This video shows the condition of the wreckage and the abundance of tropical fish gathered near the wreck site.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2009-03-01T20:10:32Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/S_cSKkEVBkw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>595</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/396</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/odAH8iQMIzo/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>2014-02-16 USS Curb Wreck - Steep &amp; Deep</video:title>
         <video:description>One of Key West&apos;s Signature Deep, Technical Wreck Dives</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2014-03-17T03:17:14Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/odAH8iQMIzo</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>173</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/409</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ixoNlw3Nk0M/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Montaje: Naufragio USS Muliphen (60 metros) - Florida, USA</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-06-14T12:39:17Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/ixoNlw3Nk0M</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>119</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/316</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/QDFDwkIwr98/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>USS Rankin Tec Scuba Dive | Site Guide and Review | Stuart, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>USS Rankin (AKA-103/LKA-103)
History

USS Rankin (AKA-103/LKA-103) was a Tolland-class attack cargo ship (later Rankin class amphibious cargo ship) named after Rankin County, Mississippi. Like all AKAs, Rankin was designed to transport military cargo and landing craft, and use the latter to land weapons, supplies, soldiers and Marines on enemy shores during amphibious operations. She was the 103rd of 114 ships eventually constructed for this purpose.

Her construction was part of the country&apos;s emergency program for replacing the hundreds of cargo ships lost to enemy attacks during World War II. The Maritime Commission administered the program and dozens of the ships it produced were acquired by the United States Navy and converted into warships. Many of these ships would be used for amphibious warfare.

Rankin&apos;s keel was laid down on 31 October 1944 at North Carolina Shipbuilding Co. in Wilmington, North Carolina. She was launched 52 days later on 22 December, and commissioned in Charleston, South Carolina on 25 February 1945. She served as a commissioned warship for a total of 21 years and five months.

Final disposal
On 24 July 1988, the ship was sunk as an artificial fishing and diving reef, six miles off the coast of Stuart, Florida. She rests on her starboard side at a depth of 130 feet at 27°12.148′N 80°06.087′WCoordinates: 27°12.148′N 80°06.087′W.[1] The site remains popular among fisherman and advanced SCUBA divers.

A sink from the ship was salvaged and is currently installed in the training room at Scuba Dive Addiction in Kissimmee, Florida</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-07-16T22:27:29Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/QDFDwkIwr98</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>270</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/246</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/AD-K8lwVXoU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>DIVING THE DEEP WRECK OF THE VITRIC OFF KEY LARGO, FLORIDA</video:title>
         <video:description>📺Subscribe To My Channel for More Awesome Diving-Related Content!
https://www.youtube.com/user/aocfishman00?sub_confirmation=1

Footage from July 2016 to the wreck of the chemical schooner barge VITRIC, lost while under tow in March 1944.  The wreck was first identified in 2000 by divers from the Association of Underwater Explorers. 

NOT FOR BROADCAST - COPYRIGHT

SHIPWRECK | WRECK DIVING| UNDERWATER | EXPLORATION | TECHNICAL DIVING | AQUATIC | SCUBA DIVING | UNDERWATER ARCHAEOLOGY | SHIPWRECK DIVING |</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-07-13T02:09:28Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/AD-K8lwVXoU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>169</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/322</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/32VM48FyCwk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>WickstromSummitFWC.wmv</video:title>
         <video:description> </video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2010-01-16T18:44:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/32VM48FyCwk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>37</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/389</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Ay_-flnHpRs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Wilkes Barre Bow Tec Wreck Scuba Dive | Key West, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>https://www.wreckwiki.com/wreck/Wilkes-Barre-Bow-Section
 
HISTORY
The U.S.S. Wilkes Barre, CL-103, was a Cleveland class light cruiser.

Dec. 24th,1943: Built and Launched by the New York Shipbuilding Corp.  Her armament consisted of twelve 6-inch guns, twelve 5-inch guns and a battery of 40 and 20-mm anti-aircraft guns.

July 1st, 1944: commissioned at the Philadelphia Navy Yard, with Captain Robert L. Porter, Jr., in command and saw quite a bit of action during World War II.

Feb. 16th, 1945: screened aircraft carriers, as their planes bombed Tokyo

Feb. 21st, 1945: called in to assist in the shore bombardment of Iwo Jima

Mar. 19th, 1945: was steaming east of Okinawa when gunners on the Wilkes Barre bagged her first enemy aircraft, a Judy dive bomber

April 1st, 1945: supported the largest American amphibious assault in history, the invasion of Okinawa

Jan. 13th, 1946, the Wilkes Barre sailed for the United States. She had received four battle stars for her World War II service and had shot down seven enemy aircraft.

Oct. 9th, 1947: Decommissioned and placed in Philadelphia

May 12th, 1972: was used as the subject for underwater explosive tests. The explosion broke the ship in two.

Her stern sank quickly, but her forward section needed an additional scuttling charge to send her to the ocean&apos;s floor.

​

Divesite:
Both bow and stern sections remain intact in 220 feet of water where she was intentionally placed so as not to be a hazard to navigation. Her stern sits on an even keel, and her bow rests on its starboard side. Because of her deep resting spot, the Wilkes Barre can only be dove by very experienced deep divers. Her superstructure can be reached at 145 feet. This huge wreck abounds with marine life, artifacts and a fascinating history.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-08-25T18:09:16Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ay_-flnHpRs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>161</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/80</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.6400</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/NqH7P5VXY6U/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Jupiter Wreck Trek</video:title>
         <video:description>During August and September, the goliath groupers start to congregate around the local wrecks, making for some excellent diving.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-08-12T17:17:26Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/NqH7P5VXY6U</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>147</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/185</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-95Sktz9CtE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Scuba Diving at Barracuda Reef, Fort Lauderdale, Florida</video:title>
         <video:description>My Wife and I did a couple of dives while spending a weekend in Ft. Lauderdale. It is a nice slow drift dive.

Surrounded by 29 mooring buoys--the first markers to be installed in Broward County--Barracuda reef is an excellent spot for fish-watching. Located a half-mile out from the John U. Lloyd State Recreational Area, this reef lies in 35 feet of water. The site has a high profile reef ledge that rises 10 to 15 feet from the bottom. This reef offers a sight similar to that of reefs in the Florida Keys with a healthy concentration of stag horn, star, and brain corals. Fish life is plentiful and lobsters, crabs, and moray eels can be found underneath ledges that rise about four feet from the bottom. Boat traffic is heavy in the area and divers should exercise caution when exploring this reef.

Filmed by Oleg Kaplun using GoPro Hero 2. Two Lights &amp; Motion Sola 2000 Lights. Backscatter Red Filter


Over Time by Audionautix is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution license (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) 
Artist: http://audionautix.com/</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2017-06-22T12:03:15Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/-95Sktz9CtE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>295</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/111</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/AP4E7BqrzJk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tenneco Towers</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-03-05T05:24:56Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/AP4E7BqrzJk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>294</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/248</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/VTDsfP0jSr8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive Davis Reef H264 Widescreen 1280x720</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-09-19T15:46:32Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/VTDsfP0jSr8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>139</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/292</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/DYAPaq8goM0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Davis Crocker Reef</video:title>
         <video:description>So I did a thing the other day, I went diving and took some video. I thought carefully about posting this since this is such an incredibly beautiful reef. So if this inspires you to visit this or any other reef, PLEASE take care of it.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-03-19T10:00:09Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/DYAPaq8goM0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>362</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/301</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/N2_GoLQkNfo/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Alligator Reef</video:title>
         <video:description>Located next to Alligator Light House</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-06-24T22:37:38Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2_GoLQkNfo</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>758</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/33</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/OLWLNui-3BE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>🤿 Molasses Reef Key Largo 2022  🐠 One of THE BEST Snorkeling &amp; Diving Spots in USA 🇺🇸</video:title>
         <video:description>Join me, The Key Largo Dude, for a beautiful day of snorkeling at the amazing Molasses Reef in Key Largo, Florida. Molasses Reef is the third largest barrier reef in the planet. 

Amazing waters, full of sharks, turtles, and tropical fish! I also found a mermaid! 

➡️ Molasses Reef in Key Largo is located on the southern side of the John Pennekamp State Park and is likely the most popular diving and snorkeling spot in the keys.
This an SPA (special protected area) within John Pennekamp Coral Reef State Park. 

With depths ranging from ten to fifty feet, there are over thirty mooring buoys marking the area that display the depth at each location.
➡️ With the variations in depth and range of reefs, wildlife, and caves, this spot is perfect for everyone from novice snorkelers and divers to those with the most experience. 
This incredible aerial and underwater footage of the Molasses Reef makes it clear why this is one of the most popular snorkel and dive spots in the United States!
Please support the Coral restoration, Coral Reefs are important ecosystems and must be protected.

💬 Let me know in the comments section below if you have visited the Molasses Reef!

I appreciate every thumbs up and would love it if you’d consider subscribing to the channel! 👉 https://www.youtube.com/TheKeyLargoDude?sub_confirmation=1

********************
Welcome to the official YouTube channel of The Key Largo Dude! 🏝

If you have ever wanted to explore the Florida Keys, this channel is a great place to see amazing footage of all the best places to visit!
➡️ My name is Chris, The Key Largo Dude, and I am excited to share videos of my adventures in the beautiful state of Florida.
A south Florida native and resident of the Keys, I have spent many years boating, fishing, and diving in the waters here and exploring all the amazing things the great outdoors in Florida have to offer.

As an Advance Scuba certified diver and an FAA-certified UAV pilot, I can bring you footage from the depths of the ocean to the blue sky above.
➡️ I have a variety of drones and cameras that I use to create these cinematic videos of the state I love so much.

If you want to join me on my adventures through the Florida Keys and beyond, please like and subscribe to stay up to date with my latest videos. Hit that bell to never miss a video! 🔔

********************
👍 Let’s Connect! Follow The Key Largo Dude on your favorite social media:

Instagram ➡️ https://www.instagram.com/the_key_largo_dude/
Twitter ➡️ https://twitter.com/Keylargodude
Facebook ➡️ https://www.facebook.com/thekeylargodude
TikTok ➡️ https://www.tiktok.com/@the_key_largo_dude

Don&apos;t forget to visit @GabyEquestrianMiami  - She is the mermaid!

********************
🎞 Equipment:
This video was filmed with a Gopro hero 10
My boat is a Seafox Traveler 226.

********************
#MolassesReef #KeyLargo #TheKeyLargoDude #JohnPennekamp #TheFloridaKeys</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-07-09T19:00:16Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/OLWLNui-3BE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>233</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/70</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ffDMomNpvKs/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Key Largo Diving - Conch Wall &amp; Snapper Ledge</video:title>
         <video:description>Filmed over just two gorgeous dives off Key Largo, Florida. 

http://gowhereitswarm.net/</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-09-09T13:10:27Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/ffDMomNpvKs</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>64</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/74</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/zoL4zTfu3hk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving the Florida Keys</video:title>
         <video:description>The Florida Keys offers enough diversity to keep divers coming back for years. From their first ocean adventure, to out-planting small Staghorn Corals in order to help replenish coral life on the reefs, to identifying hundreds of species of marine life, to some of the world’s foremost wreck diving, the Keys offer something for everyone.

Learn more about visiting the Florida Keys: http://www.fla-keys.com/


Subscribe to our channel: https://www.youtube.com/padi 

Connect with us on social:
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PADI 
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PADItv
Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/PADI
Website: https://www.padi.com</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2018-02-22T17:23:37Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/zoL4zTfu3hk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>16</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/59</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/LNkeBpf2F8o/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Christ of the Deep (a.k.a. Christ of the Abyss) statue, Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-09-19T16:01:33Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/LNkeBpf2F8o</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>139</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/54</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/O1Qm_Pt3Ry0/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>French Reef Dive in Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description>French Reef is one of the most spectacular reef areas in the Florida Keys. There are dozens of ledges, tunnels, and caves to explore; most large enough to swim through. Bring your flash light and dive lights to check for fish inside the arches.
French Reef is known for its many caves and arches, easily accessible even to novice divers. At the south end is Hourglass Cave, named for its shape. Christmas Tree Cave is named for the large conical star coral mound that rises over the top located at the beginning of the coral formation.

Type: Reef
Min. Depth: 15ft. / 5m
Max. Depth: 40 ft. / 13m
Skill Level:  Open Water Diver</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-10-20T16:21:06Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/O1Qm_Pt3Ry0</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>58</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/69</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/w2Qs7Kcp7Mc/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Snapper Ledge, Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-09-19T15:46:32Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/w2Qs7Kcp7Mc</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>89</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/58</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/69kiqloYCQE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Dive Minnow Caves, North Dry Rocks,  Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-09-19T15:46:32Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/69kiqloYCQE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>180</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/66</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/1cTgvrVU4Xc/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Sand Island reef Key Largo</video:title>
         <video:description>A dive on the Sand Island Reef off of Key Largo. #scuba #scubadiving #reef #coral #atlanticocean #florida #floridakeys #keylargo #fish #sealife #shark #nurseshark #morayeel #butterflyfish #filefish #parrotfish</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2020-11-22T04:18:52Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/1cTgvrVU4Xc</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>411</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/41</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/u_BFs1J8P0Y/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>The Nursery Reef at Pompano Beach</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-10-04T21:32:30Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/u_BFs1J8P0Y</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>211</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/95</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/SdjXbLrSJf8/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Crab Cove Reef   Deerfield Beach</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-05-19T19:28:06Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/SdjXbLrSJf8</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>240</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/36</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/LaxeMwED4MI/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Lighthouse Ledge / Razzle Dazzle - Pompano Beach FL - Scubatyme</video:title>
         <video:description>Easy reef diving with Scubatyme Charters. Eels, lobsters, sharks, crab</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-01-14T04:13:21Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/LaxeMwED4MI</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>74</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/2</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/2DUROfPcbic/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Abbey Too Reef</video:title>
         <video:description>Abbey Too Reef is a section of the outer reef, running parallel to the shoreline. The highest concentration of sea life and coral cover is on the western facing ledge (main ledge). There is a wide variety of reef fish. Grouper, snapper, jacks, barracuda, and moray eels. Trumpetfish and spotfin drums have also been seen here. There is lobster in the caves along the base and top of the reef. The second dive will be on a different reef with a similar profile.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-10-19T22:25:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/2DUROfPcbic</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>54</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/367</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/DFsBY_HhVQk/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>🤿 SNORKELING CARYSFORT REEF and REEF LIGHT!  in John Pennekamp coral reef state park 🪸 Key Largo!</video:title>
         <video:description>Carysfort Reef 2022. The Florida Keys, We went Snorkeling  in Carysfort Reef which is part of John Pennekamp coral reef state park, in Key Largo Florida, this reef is one of the most beautiful reefs in the USA. A hidden secret not frequented by many dive operators. 

In This video we are snorkeling Carysfort Reef, the northern part of the park. Carysfort It is a shallow reef perfect for snorkelers and the water is crystal clear! 

We saw abundant sea life including huge Tarpon as well as a couple of nurse sharks, and turtles. 

We also snorkeled under the old Carysfort reef lighthouse and saw hundreds of fish, in the shade.

💬 Let me know what you think of this video in the comment section below.

I appreciate every thumbs up and would love it if you’d consider subscribing to the channel! 👉 https://www.youtube.com/TheKeyLargoDude?sub_confirmation=1

********************
Welcome to the official YouTube channel of The Key Largo Dude! 🏝

If you have ever wanted to explore the Florida Keys, this channel is a great place to see amazing footage of all the best places to visit!
➡️ My name is Chris, The Key Largo Dude, and I am excited to share videos of my adventures in the beautiful state of Florida.
A south Florida native and resident of the Keys, I have spent many years boating, fishing, and diving in the waters here and exploring all the amazing things the great outdoors in Florida have to offer.

As an Advance Scuba certified diver and an FAA-certified UAV pilot, I can bring you footage from the depths of the ocean to the blue sky above.
➡️ I have a variety of drones and cameras that I use to create these cinematic videos of the state I love so much.

If you want to join me on my adventures through the Florida Keys and beyond, please like and subscribe to stay up to date with my latest videos. Hit that bell to never miss a video! 🔔

********************
👍 Let’s Connect! Follow The Key Largo Dude on your favorite social media:

Instagram ➡️ https://www.instagram.com/the_key_largo_dude/
Twitter ➡️ https://twitter.com/Keylargodude
Facebook ➡️ https://www.facebook.com/thekeylargodude
TikTok ➡️ https://www.tiktok.com/@the_key_largo_dude

********************
🎞 Equipment: Gopro Hero 10


********************
#johnpennekamp  #carysfortreef #TheKeyLargoDude #KeyLargo #TheFloridaKeys</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-07-01T19:00:05Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/DFsBY_HhVQk</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>180</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/385</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/GqAKUxLp5TM/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Snorkeling LOOE KEY REEF | Florida Keys Snorkeling | Thriving Reef and Corals</video:title>
         <video:description>In this episode, we head out to Looe Key Reef for a snorkeling trip. Looe Key Reef is located just off of Big Pine Key and is home to many different species of fish, coral, and sharks. One of the nicest spots for snorkeling in the Florida Keys!

Follow Me:
► Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/seabassadventures/
► TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@seabass_adventures
► Discord: https://discord.gg/mBAj2mUCux

► My Website: https://seabassadventures.godaddysites.com/

Fishing Gear:
► Penn Battle II 6000: https://amzn.to/3bIw7PU
► Redfish Extreme: https://bassproshops.vzck.net/5byBJn
► Yellowtail Hooks: https://bassproshops.vzck.net/BXOYM9
► 20 lb Leader: https://amzn.to/30mnGHJ
► 50 lb Leader: https://amzn.to/3wRlyUK
► Main Line: https://amzn.to/3ELHO4R
► Ballyhoop Net: https://amzn.to/3CjLbyz

Camera Gear (at time of upload):
► Main camera: https://amzn.to/3Hosq0p
► Backup Camera: https://amzn.to/3q809Fc
► Extra Batteries: https://amzn.to/3bIzfv8
► Backup Camera: https://amzn.to/3k8YtaQ
► Camera Mounts and Accessories: https://amzn.to/3BQxdE1
► Drone: https://amzn.to/2Yk98I7
► Micro SD Card: https://amzn.to/3ou8HUG
► Editing Software: https://www.blackmagicdesign.com/products/davinciresolve/

Diving Gear (at time of upload):
► Mask: https://amzn.to/3GTGPBv
► Fins: https://amzn.to/3o0Lkld
► Gloves: https://amzn.to/3CNGTQU
► Dive Socks: https://amzn.to/3CO2lp1
► Snorkel: https://amzn.to/3CPfhLk

Note: The links above are Amazon Associate/Bass Pro Shops Associate Links and they help support the channel

Music Credits:

Music from Uppbeat (free for Creators!):
http://uppbeat.io/t/infraction/ultraviolet
License code: P4G5MCFMIKOW0ALC

Music from Uppbeat (free for Creators!):
https://uppbeat.io/t/nick-petrov/we-can-dream
License code: GHHX8FABDFHG1RAA</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-04-06T23:59:48Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/GqAKUxLp5TM</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>264</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/130</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/FJrmGTynnBg/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Radio Towers Dive in Miami</video:title>
         <video:description>The 19 steel and concrete radio towers were sunk in 1988. The pyramids rest in 50 feet of water and each rises about 20 feet from the bottom. There are several other wrecks (Miss Patricia/Miss Karline) and artificial reefs (Rock Pile) nearby. All the large and smaller concrete blocks have created an area where juvenile fish have great chances to grow, being fed and breed. The site is often used by navigational trainee divers as the antennas are still capable of interfering with your compass.

Type: Artificial reef
Min. Depth: 45 ft. / 14m
Max. Depth: 45 ft. / 14m
Skill Level: Open Water Diver</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2016-10-19T22:03:51Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/FJrmGTynnBg</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>55</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/31</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/FfFh5T7qOPQ/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>The world&apos;s first underwater cemetery - BBC REEL</video:title>
         <video:description>The Neptune Memorial Reef, located off the coast of Key Biscayne in Florida, is the world’s first underwater cemetery. The eco-friendly memorial site is designed to look like a sunken city, modelled after the Lost City of Atlantis.

This unique artificial reef is currently the resting place for the cremated remains of more than 1,000 people. Once complete, it will house 250,000 memorial placements as well as thousands of different marine creatures across 16 acres of ocean floor.


Video by Izabela Cardoso &amp; Fernando Teixeira
Executive Producer: Camelia Sadeghzadeh

#bbcreel #bbc #bbcnews</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2022-04-06T14:00:10Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/FfFh5T7qOPQ</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>369</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/107</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/wkDjXdZsdUU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>This is Emerald Reef, Miami Beach  -  Part 1</video:title>
         <video:description>This is Emerald Reef, Miami Beach - Part 1

Reservations:
LuxyDiver.com
305.322.4425</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-05-19T20:06:47Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/wkDjXdZsdUU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>292</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/139</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/5A-wQIk7Hms/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Scuba Diving Miami, Florida USA (Neptune Memorial Reef, Darrell Ledge, Flamingo Reef, Belcher Wreck)</video:title>
         <video:description>Recorded 30-31 March 2024 on an Insta360 Ace Pro

#scuba #diving #underwater #miami #florida #shark #morayeel #barracuda #neptunememorialreef

Thanks to @TarpoonLagoonFilms 

If you enjoyed this video please feel free to check out my other underwater adventures at https://www.youtube.com/@saltwatervagabond 

Feel free to subscribe to be kept up to date with new content.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-04-01T17:55:01Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/5A-wQIk7Hms</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>298</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/225</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/b-IAyV39yPw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Pompano Sunkist Reef</video:title>
         <video:description>Scuba Diving in Pompano Beach. Reef Dive. GoPro Hero 4 With Backflip Filter
South Florida Diving Headquarters</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2015-08-18T00:04:59Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/b-IAyV39yPw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>141</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/229</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/w0ExmPRPdjw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>South Florida Reef Diving- Pompano Beach Florida- pompano trench - razzle dazzle - Sunkist</video:title>
         <video:description>BackTip Dpv, Queen Angle, 3rd largest barrier reef in the world</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-07-26T01:00:39Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/w0ExmPRPdjw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>188</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/220</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bvOkynCf5Tw/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Boca Raton Chalfonte &amp; Boca Artificial Reef Ledge Dives 6-17-23.  Hammerhead sighting!</video:title>
         <video:description>Turtles, Lionfish, Morey Eel, Lobster, Nurse Shark, and Hammerhead Shark captured...</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-06-24T22:15:13Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/bvOkynCf5Tw</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>328</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/315</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/tb3LFxXJjx4/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving Flower Garden &amp; Breakers Reef: West Palm Beach, FL</video:title>
         <video:description>Awesome conditions for a mid-December dive day!</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-12-17T02:34:48Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/tb3LFxXJjx4</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>306</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/314</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/eecEolxxIhU/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Juno Ledge Scuba Diving, Jupiter Florida 4K | Pura Vida Divers | West Palm Beach @OlegKaplun</video:title>
         <video:description>This is my first video with GoPro Hero 7 Black, and new backscatter red filters. Lessons Learned :-).

Located hear Palm Beach off the coast of Juno Beach, the Juno Ledge features a number of excellent scuba diving spots. One such spot, Lee&apos;s Ledge, is a 60 to 85-foot dive with visibility in the 80 to 100-foot range. This area is home to loggerhead turtles and nurse sharks, as well as the goliath grouper.</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2019-07-05T11:45:49Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/eecEolxxIhU</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>225</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/284</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/MOakazxtrfE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Hole in the wall ( Jupiter dive with Narcosis dive company ) tec dive with mandatory safety stop</video:title>
         <video:description></video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2021-10-24T22:13:55Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/MOakazxtrfE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>173</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/238</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/kcObJrBojNE/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Tumble Rocks and Lynn’s Reef, Boynton Beach, FL, May 2023</video:title>
         <video:description>Reef Diving #scuba #underwater #underwaterworld #underwaterdiving #sea #seacreatures #scubadiving #reef #reeffish #underwater #scuba #scubadiving #sea #seacreatures #underwaterdiving #reef #reeffish #divingtrip #divingisfun #underwaterworld #diving
#ocean #sealife #underwaterphotography #underwaterphotos #underwaterphotographer #boatdiving #beautifulscenery #underwatershots #underwaterambience #underwaterworld #underwaterbeauty</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-05-09T01:11:37Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/kcObJrBojNE</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>318</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/240</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/vVEuQNikCas/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Gazebo and Lynn’s Reef Boynton Beach, FL 12.10.2023</video:title>
         <video:description>Gazebo and Lynn’s Reef Boynton Beach, FL 12.10.2023

#Diving #scuba #underwater #underwaterworld #underwaterdiving #sea #seacreatures #scubadiving #wreckdive #wreckdiving #underwater #scuba #scubadiving #sea #seacreatures #underwaterdiving #reef #reeffish #divingtrip #divingisfun #underwaterworld #diving
#ocean #sealife #underwaterphotography #underwaterphotos #underwaterphotographer #boatdiving #beautifulscenery #underwatershots #underwaterambience #underwaterworld #underwaterbeauty</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2023-12-24T19:51:45Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/vVEuQNikCas</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>164</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/224</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/KEe957XdFJA/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>5 21 24 Delray Ledge</video:title>
         <video:description>Out on a Tuesday and amazingly, the water temps were warmer than on Sunday.  Fun with Turtles, sharks, and more turtles.  #diving #drift #soflo #boyntonbeach #splashdown #turtle #boyntonbeachfl #shark</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2024-05-21T23:54:49Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/KEe957XdFJA</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>814</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
  <url>
       <loc>https://divers-hub.com/SiteDetails/271</loc>
       <lastmod>2025-07-08T04:19:29+00:00</lastmod>
       <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
       <priority>0.5120</priority>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/P1s1da9wSfY/mqdefault.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Diving in Palm Beach - Shark Canyon and Spud Barge</video:title>
         <video:description>Diving Shark Canyon and Spud Barge on 12.07.2012. Encounters with sharks, turtles, goliath groupers and more!</video:description>
         <video:publication_date>2012-12-08T03:57:03Z</video:publication_date>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/P1s1da9wSfY</video:player_loc>
         <video:duration>248</video:duration>
       </video:video>
  </url>
</urlset>